<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debian on Deimosfr Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/tags/debian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Debian on Deimosfr Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 07:44:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.deimos.fr/tags/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do not waste time with grep anymore, use tag</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2016/06/18/do-not-waste-time-with-grep-anymore-use-tag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2016 07:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2016/06/18/do-not-waste-time-with-grep-anymore-use-tag/</guid>
      <description>Long time since my last post. This one is not very technical post, but it&amp;rsquo;s a nice to have solution if you use grep usually. Are not you fed up to type vim  and search the line after a grep command ? If yes, this post is for you.
First of all, you may know that an alternative more user friendly to grep exist, called ag (perf comparison). I really like ag and grep, but something make me loose my time since several years and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure it&amp;rsquo;s your case too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero downtime upgrade with Ansible and HAProxy</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/21/zero-downtime-upgrade-with-ansible-and-haproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/21/zero-downtime-upgrade-with-ansible-and-haproxy/</guid>
      <description>Some of you may not be familiar with the terms &amp;ldquo;Rolling upgrade&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Rolling restart&amp;rdquo;. This is the action of upgrading or restarting a cluster without service interruption (alias zero downtime). In most cases, this is done node by node, but in fact it depends of the technology you&amp;rsquo;re managing and the number of active nodes in your cluster.
At Nousmotards we have several Java Spring Boot applications running. Restarting one application can take up to 1 min.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Ansible Consul Template role</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/11/27/upgrading-ansible-consul-template-role/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 21:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/11/27/upgrading-ansible-consul-template-role/</guid>
      <description>As I wanted to upgrade it and because it has been asked several time, I upgraded the consul-template Ansible role to manage official binaries (and upgrades). Here are the new vars:
consul_template_version: &amp;#39;0.11.0&amp;#39; consul_template_arch: &amp;#39;linux_amd64&amp;#39; consul_template_http_src: &amp;quot;https://github.com/hashicorp/consul-template/releases/download/v{{consul_template_version}}/consul_template_{{consul_template_version}}_{{consul_template_arch}}.zip&amp;quot;  You can of course find the role to Ansible Galaxy: https://galaxy.ansible.com/detail#/role/3451
I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy this new version :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian Jessie and MacBookPro 13 (2015/12,1) with Kernel 4</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/04/28/debian-jessie-and-macbookpro-13-2015121-with-kernel-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/04/28/debian-jessie-and-macbookpro-13-2015121-with-kernel-4/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the chance to get the latest MacBookPro 13 for my new work at Criteo. If you follow me and remember, this is not the first time I want to use Debian on a new MacBookPro version.
Overview History repeats itself and as you can think, some things are not working out of the box on Debian Jessie. Here are the issues I encountered and how i could fix some of them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian 8 (Jessie) is out !!!</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/04/26/debian-8-jessie-is-out-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 21:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/04/26/debian-8-jessie-is-out-2/</guid>
      <description>Debian 8 is out ! After several months of freeze, it&amp;rsquo;s now ready. I&amp;rsquo;m really happy about that version because MySecureShell is finally available in the mainstream packages and the second thing is MariaDB available in the latest stable version (10).
Unfortunately, Docker is not present because it has too fast cycles to be stable (source). Thanks to Debian teams for this amazing work once again :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: Neo4j role available on Ansible Galaxy</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/02/27/ansible-neo4j-role-available-on-ansible-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/02/27/ansible-neo4j-role-available-on-ansible-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>For a new project (will talk about it later), I needed to use Neo4J (graph database if you don&amp;rsquo;t know it yet).
I tried to cover more features than the current existing Ansible roles available on Ansible Galaxy. More will come in the next weeks. I also tried to make it simple to install it and do not force dependencies at maximum. Here are parameters you can set:
# Select neo4j version neo4j_package: neo4j # community version #neo4j_package: neo4j-advanced #neo4j_package: neo4j-enterprise # Neo4j spatial plugin neo4j_install_spatial: false neo4j_spatial_version: &amp;#39;0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: LXC role updated for Jessie</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/02/25/ansible-lxc-role-updated-for-jessie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 11:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/02/25/ansible-lxc-role-updated-for-jessie/</guid>
      <description>Since several weeks, I&amp;rsquo;m playing a lot with Debian Jessie as a server. I discovered some bugs, reported them to Debian, they&amp;rsquo;ve been fixed etc&amp;hellip;good news! I also wanted to test the new version of LXC.
So I decided to upgrade my 2 personal servers to Jessie. But that wasn&amp;rsquo;t so easy with Systemd. I still encounter non critical issues and going to prepare report bugs for Debian (cgroups issues with systemd).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate changelog from git commits and integrate with Sphinxdoc</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/02/11/generate-changelog-from-git-commits-and-integrate-with-sphinxdoc-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/02/11/generate-changelog-from-git-commits-and-integrate-with-sphinxdoc-2/</guid>
      <description>For another personal project (that I can&amp;rsquo;t talk about for the moment ;-)), I wanted to have a Changelog file to get a better following of the infrastructure evolution (configuration management, scripts&amp;hellip;all under git). Of course the documentation is very important, but when you do not write it at the same time you&amp;rsquo;re building the infrastructure, it may be complex to remember each little things you&amp;rsquo;ve done. That&amp;rsquo;s why a Changelog can help to understand how the infrastructure has been built step by step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offload SSL with HAProxy</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/01/27/offload-ssl-with-haproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 11:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/01/27/offload-ssl-with-haproxy/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I already talked about offloading SSL with Nginx. I also wanted to try it with HAProxy which can be more interesting in some cases.
The good On HAProxy, the good thing is the simplicity to do it. First of all you need to have at least the version 1.5 of HAProxy so to get SSL support. Then you only need those lines to offload SSL:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple EC2 snapshot released !</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/01/20/simple-ec2-snapshot-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 11:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/01/20/simple-ec2-snapshot-released/</guid>
      <description>For my company, I recently had to find a good solution to make Snapshots from Instance IDs or from tags on AWS. I made several searches but unfortunately didn&amp;rsquo;t find what I was searching for.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I started to make a tool to do this kind of job. It&amp;rsquo;s written in Python and requires the Boto library. Here is what you can do with Simple EC2 snapshots:
 Hot snapshots (by default) and Cold snapshots   Multiple instances snapshot in one line   Detection of doubles   Filters by tags (allowing wildcards) or by instance IDs   Credentials file multiple with profiles   Limit the number of snapshots   Restrict snapshots to data disks only   The tool is open source and can be downloaded on GitHub :-).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packer: build multiple images easily</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/01/16/packer-build-multiple-images-easily/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2015/01/16/packer-build-multiple-images-easily/</guid>
      <description>Packer is one of the tools I&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past to build VirtualBox boxes. You can find what I&amp;rsquo;ve done on my GitHub account.
For Smash project, I wanted to make a packer configuration to manage Docker and VirtualBox. I also wanted to call Ansible to build specific images for each needs. The goal is to be able to build cloud image ready to start, without any special dependencies. This because I need different usages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: Fluentd and Kibana playbooks updated</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/12/09/ansible-fluentd-and-kibana-playbooks-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 11:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/12/09/ansible-fluentd-and-kibana-playbooks-updated/</guid>
      <description>Following the deployment blog post I made on ES/Kibana/Fluentd, I released new version of Fluentd and Kibana playbooks to support the latests versions of themselves and ElasticSearch.
ElasticSearch 1.4 version is ,out which doesn&amp;rsquo;t changed anything for the deployment. However Kibana requires to enable an ElasticSearch configuration option now, to work properly. I updated the Kibana playbook for it.
On its side, Fluentd has the major release 2.0 out and I updated Ansible playbook for the best integration with Debian Wheezy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFS: recover your client connexion when server was down</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/11/25/nfs-recover-your-client-connexion-when-server-was-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/11/25/nfs-recover-your-client-connexion-when-server-was-down/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the case, where I lost connexion of my NFS client connexion because NFS server crashed. The problem I had is simple, some of clients couldn&amp;rsquo;t recover their connexion because the old one was still shown as already connected.
And when I tried to remount NFS clients connexions, I got:
mount.nfs: mount(2): Protocol not supported mount.nfs: trying text-based options &amp;#39;udp,sec=sys,rsize=8192,wsize=8192,intr,hard,addr=10.0.0.1&amp;#39; mount.nfs: prog 100003, trying vers=3, prot=17 mount.nfs: trying 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian Jessie is frozen</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/11/09/debian-jessie-is-freezen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 11:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/11/09/debian-jessie-is-freezen/</guid>
      <description>Jessie is now frozen!!! Here is the news.
That mean only limited updates can be done:
  targeted fixes for release critical bugs (i.e., bugs of severity critical, grave, and serious) in all packages (applies during the entire freeze (ok for TPU));
  fixes for severity: important bugs in packages of priority: optional or extra, only when this can be done via unstable (until the 5th of December 2014);</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack Summit in Paris on Monday!</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/11/01/openstack-summit-in-paris-on-monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 11:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/11/01/openstack-summit-in-paris-on-monday/</guid>
      <description>OpenStack Summit will take place in Paris in 2 days! I&amp;rsquo;m excited to be able to participate. Big thanks to eNovance/RedHat for it!
To know more about the event, please follow the link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic package creation, which one to choose?</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/30/automatic-package-creation-which-one-to-choose/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/30/automatic-package-creation-which-one-to-choose/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently developing a complete packaging stack based on Docker to easily make different kind of packages for several Linux distributions. This for MySecureShell project.
This stack will be used to build packages in destination of upstream Linux distribution packages. But I&amp;rsquo;d like to provide a simpler and faster way to create custom repositories mainly for Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS and Fedora. In addition if packages could be automatically created when a new tag is pushed to the GitHub account, it would be perfect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MySecureShell finally available in official Debian repository</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/28/mysecureshell-finally-available-in-official-debian-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/28/mysecureshell-finally-available-in-official-debian-repository/</guid>
      <description>You may know that I&amp;rsquo;m one of the 2 founders of MySecureShell. Around 6 years ago, we made a quick try to send MySecureShell to Debian and didn&amp;rsquo;t make enough efforts to make it possible.
This time I worked hard to make this happen. Thanks a lot to Gonéri Le bouder, a colleague and Debian dev to make it possible and helped me to do it fast, before Jessie freeze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yosemite and Refind: recover your Linux boot</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/22/yosemite-and-refind-recover-your-linux-boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/22/yosemite-and-refind-recover-your-linux-boot/</guid>
      <description>You may upgrade your Mac OS X version to Yosemite (10.10) and saw you dual boot with Linux not working anymore :-(.
That&amp;rsquo;s because Apple made changes and Refind is not yet ready for it. So here is the solution to get your dual boot half back. It won&amp;rsquo;t fully work as expected, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to boot to Linux with Refind and Mac OS X with the alt key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tig: browse your Git repositories in curses</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/16/tig-browse-your-git-repositories-in-curses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 10:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/16/tig-browse-your-git-repositories-in-curses/</guid>
      <description>A colleague talked to me about this tool this week and I felt in love. It helps to easily navigate into your git repository. You can have a look on last log and directly in the same interface the diff of the current commit. I&amp;rsquo;ve attached one screenshot to let you see how cool it is.
The are also a lot of other features but just for browsing purpose. You can&amp;rsquo;t update or make changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fig: use docker to create a containers’ stack</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/14/fig-use-docker-to-create-a-containers-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/14/fig-use-docker-to-create-a-containers-stack/</guid>
      <description>Fig is a fast, isolated development environments using Docker. For some features, it can be compared to Vagrant where the Dockerfike is not enough powerful to build multiple instances.
For example, let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to test a new product version of a software like MediaWiki and you want to build the complete stack. So you may need to have several tools categories (depending of the usage):
 Web: Nginx, PHP-FPM, Varnish App Cahing: Redis Search: ElasticSearch  In Vagrant you can natively build 3 VM and interconnect them without the need of additional tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aptly: swiss army knife for Debian repository management</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/12/aptly-swiss-army-knife-for-debian-repository-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 10:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/12/aptly-swiss-army-knife-for-debian-repository-management/</guid>
      <description>I recently discover Aptly which permit to manage local Debian repositories. I waited this kind of tools during several years and now I&amp;rsquo;m really happy.
It is able to manage several repositories, making snapshots, merging snapshots, diff between 2 snapshots, filtering packages to avoid downloading unwanted ones&amp;hellip;.
This is perfect when you want to test before upgrading a critical infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FIO: Bench IO disks</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/06/fio-bench-io-disks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 10:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/06/fio-bench-io-disks/</guid>
      <description>The first thing you generally want to do when you have any new Storage system like SSD, Disk arrays or a Cluster Ceph, is benching. You will want to know how can read and write throughput. FIO is able to do that for you, here is an example:
[global] ioengine=libaio invalidate=1 ramp_time=5 direct=1 size=5G runtime=300 time_based directory=/home [seq-read] rw=read bs=64K stonewall [rand-read] rw=randread bs=4K stonewall [seq-write] rw=write bs=64K stonewall [rand-write] rw=randwrite bs=4K stonewall  You then will have a good output of everything you need to know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx: enable HSTS (force SSL for users)</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/18/nginx-enable-hsts-force-ssl-for-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 10:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/18/nginx-enable-hsts-force-ssl-for-users/</guid>
      <description>I recently heard of HSTS which is a way to force users to come back to your website in SSL if they&amp;rsquo;ve already be to HTTPS once. It is simple, just add this line:
# HSTS (force users to come in SSL if they&amp;#39;ve already been once) add_header Strict-Transport-Security &amp;quot;max-age=31536000; includeSubdomains&amp;quot;;  If you want to have an overview of a complete configuration with it, look at the my wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedbacks: Upgrading from PHP 5.4 to 5.5</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/16/feedback-moving-from-php-5-4-to-5-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/16/feedback-moving-from-php-5-4-to-5-5/</guid>
      <description>Because of the recent announce from DotDeb about PHP 5.6 availability on Debian, I saw that I totally forgot to move from PHP 5.4 to 5.5.
As I&amp;rsquo;m hosting several WordPress, Mediawiki, Piwik and other PHP web software, I was not very comfortable with that migration. I knew that the major change was on PHP cache. I was intensively using APC cache but in PHP 5.5, it is deprecated and Opcache replace it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ElasticSearch setup HA and basic usages</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/10/elasticsearch-setup-ha-and-basic-usages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/10/elasticsearch-setup-ha-and-basic-usages/</guid>
      <description>I recently played with ElasticSearch Cluster and I totally fall in love! How easy it is, everything is automatic, it works perfectly, wowwww!!!
I made a little documentation on how to setup one, you can find it there.
ElasticSearch is a really powerful solution and I really like working with it. If you&amp;rsquo;re searching a full text search solution, try ElasticSearch, you&amp;rsquo;ll be happy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packer: 1 command line to create a Debian VirtualBox/Vagrant box</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/04/packer-easily-create-a-debian-virtualboxvagrant-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/04/packer-easily-create-a-debian-virtualboxvagrant-box/</guid>
      <description>I recently wanted to update my Vagrant box running Debian Wheezy. The problem is, the box size is growing on each updates for several reasons. And I prefer to create a new box from scratch on any new Debian release.
Starting from scratch each time is a little bit boring, that&amp;rsquo;s why I created a preseed file (french). That made the install automatically, however I always had to do other step by hands (or need to write a script for it).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naemon/Nagios: LXC check resources</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/02/naemonnagios-lxc-check-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/02/naemonnagios-lxc-check-resources/</guid>
      <description>You may know that I really like LXC and the major problem when you want to use that solution in production is: how do you monitor memory and CPU?
Regarding the CPU side, I do not have an easy answer for the moment :-(. However regarding the memory, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a Nagios/Naemon check which will check the memory (RAM) and SWAP of a container. Here is how to use it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC 1.0 on Debian Wheezy</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/29/lxc-1-0-on-debian-wheezy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/29/lxc-1-0-on-debian-wheezy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m using for my own servers LXC for about a year now. I&amp;rsquo;m still fed up about bugs introduced by the beta version of LXC (0.8b) present in Debian Wheezy. As now LXC project has released a stable version, I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at the Debian backports, but didn&amp;rsquo;t have any chance to find a newer version on it :-(. However, a version 1.0.4 exist on Debian Jessie. I took the Debian sources and recompiled them on Wheezy (available here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nagios/Naemon: Free Mobile SMS notification</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/27/nagiosnaemon-free-mobile-notification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 10:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/27/nagiosnaemon-free-mobile-notification/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Free Mobile (French mobile provider) to provides an SMS API. I enabled it for my own monitoring escalation, just in case I have problem receiving emails.
I&amp;rsquo;ve made a short documentation on how to setup SMS notification through Free Mobile for Nagios or Naemon (in french).
Enjoy :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring: switching from Nagios to Naemon (not Shinken or Sensu)</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/25/monitoring-switching-from-nagios-feedbacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/25/monitoring-switching-from-nagios-feedbacks/</guid>
      <description>I am using Nagios for about 8 years now for personal and professional usage. What I can say is, this is a super product, old and stable but not as scalable as I would like. We&amp;rsquo;re in the age of Cloud computing and in my opinion we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to take care about backup and monitoring in now days, this should be automatic.
I was searching a solution for my personal usages, that&amp;rsquo;s why I first wanted a lightweight solution but with enough maturity to auto discover my newly created LXC containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Book: MariaDB High Performance available for pre-order</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/23/my-book-mariadb-high-performance-available-for-pre-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/23/my-book-mariadb-high-performance-available-for-pre-order/</guid>
      <description>All, I&amp;rsquo;m proud to announce my first book available for pre-order! I&amp;rsquo;m really happy to have finished it and see after several months of hard work that it will be soon available.
Who is this book for?
 MariaDB High Performance is aimed at system administrators/architects or DBAs who want to learn more about how to grow their current infrastructure to support larger traffic.
Before beginning with this book, we expect you to be well–practised with MySQL/MariaDB for common usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gogs: easily install on Debian Wheezy</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/21/gogs-easily-install-on-debian-wheezy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 10:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/21/gogs-easily-install-on-debian-wheezy/</guid>
      <description>I recently talked about Gogs and really like this solution. The main problem I encounter was the current stable version which may not be usable on Debian.
Here is a quick solution to make it work. First of all, install git:
apt-get install git  Then you can download the latest compiled version directly from gobuild.
wget http://gobuild.io/github.com/gogits/gogs/master/linux/amd64 -O output.zip unzip output.zip ./start.sh  You can now access to port 3000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: Fluentd playbook</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/13/fluentd-ansible-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/13/fluentd-ansible-playbook/</guid>
      <description>In the previous posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve introduced my Ansible playbooks for kibana and Elasticsearch.
You may now be happy to know that I&amp;rsquo;ve made an Ansible playbook for Fluentd as well. If you still don&amp;rsquo;t see what those tree ansible playbook can do when they are combined together, you&amp;rsquo;ll see in the next post :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: ElasticSearch playbook</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/09/ansible-elasticsearch-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 10:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/09/ansible-elasticsearch-playbook/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;m an Ansible fan, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a playbook for it available on GitHub and on the Ansible Galaxy. You&amp;rsquo;ll be able to add additional plugins like Head, Curator, Mavel&amp;hellip;
I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dnsmasq and dhclient: use a specific DNS for a specific domain</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/07/dnsmasq-and-dhclient-use-a-specific-dns-for-a-specific-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 10:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/07/dnsmasq-and-dhclient-use-a-specific-dns-for-a-specific-domain/</guid>
      <description>My use case is specific but not isolated. When I&amp;rsquo;m at work, I&amp;rsquo;m connected to my VPN at home. I have a specific DNS at home for my domain in deimos.lan and this is very useful to avoid me to remind all the IP of the services I have.
Sometimes, I want to connect to a home service from the VPN, but my bookmarked links have my home DNS which are unknown from the DNS at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new toy: Ubiquiti mPower</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/05/ubiquiti-mpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/05/ubiquiti-mpower/</guid>
      <description>Ubiquiti brings software that are easy to install on Windows and Mac OS. However as it is strongly recommended to let this software always up, it&amp;rsquo;s preferable to have a Linux version to run it in a container or a virtual machine. That&amp;rsquo;s why I decided to install it for a powerstrip mPower on Debian inside LXC.
The documentation is very poor, that&amp;rsquo;s why I made this one for those who want to do like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seafile: can’t use client? Use webdav standard!</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/01/seafile-cant-use-client-use-websav-standard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 10:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/01/seafile-cant-use-client-use-websav-standard/</guid>
      <description>Seafile is a Google Drive replacement. If you missed m&amp;rsquo;y previous blog post on it, you can find it here.
I really like Seafile even if a search feature is missing :-(. Seafile client is unfortunately not an available solution on all software proposing a cloud connection for sharing files.
Hopefully an alternative exists using Webdav protocol. It is not activated by default on Seafile but can easily be enable. Here is how to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systemd: how to debug a failed boot</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/07/28/systemd-how-to-debug-a-failed-boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/07/28/systemd-how-to-debug-a-failed-boot/</guid>
      <description>I recently switched my laptop from InitV to Systemd. And things didn&amp;rsquo;t happened as expected. That&amp;rsquo;s why I need to deep dive into Systemd issues and understand why it wasn&amp;rsquo;t working. I got problems like this:
Failed to get D-Bus connection: No connection to service manager.  And hopefully I found very good documentations on Internet (and especially on Arch wiki). I&amp;rsquo;ve made a summary on my wiki if you want to know how to diagnose a Systemd issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC: ressources statistics</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/16/lxc-ressources-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/16/lxc-ressources-statistics/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to find a way to properly view resources (memory/CPU/IO) usages or configuration. For that I need to use cgroups. But the problem are on free, top, htop or common any tools, as they do not get the real informations of the container.
We&amp;rsquo;re in fact waiting on a lot of work on the kernel side or systemd side. More information&amp;rsquo;s can be found here. Another solution that permit to bind a socks inside containers exists called CGManager, however classical tools doesn&amp;rsquo;t use it to get informations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from KVM to LXC…feedbacks</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/10/migrating-from-kvm-to-lxc-feedbacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/10/migrating-from-kvm-to-lxc-feedbacks/</guid>
      <description>I recently migrated this server to a new one. New hardware, better performance, less power consumption etc&amp;hellip;Thanks Online.
I&amp;rsquo;m already using LXC on my home server and see the benefits for 8 months ago. That&amp;rsquo;s why I decided to migrate this server to LXC as well. The difference here is that I wanted to migrate my VM from KVM. All my KVM VM are on Debian Wheezy so that was pretty easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: LXC role v1.1</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/02/ansible-lxc-role-v1-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/02/ansible-lxc-role-v1-1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated my LXC role for ansible. You can get it like that:
ansible-galaxy install deimosfr.lxc  Here is the change log:
+ Adding new parameters for dnsmasq and interfaces + Adding new prequesite to avoid unwanted modules to load in the latest kernel versions = Corrected networking configuration issue = Templates do not create @LOCALSTATEDIR@ folder anymore  It works perfectly on my new Dedibox :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: my first playbook is for LXC</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/15/ansible-my-first-playbook-is-for-lxc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/15/ansible-my-first-playbook-is-for-lxc/</guid>
      <description>I started to play with Ansible a little bit more than a week ago and I really enjoy it compared to Puppet. I still do not have all my reflex that I can have on Puppet, however what I can say is how easy it is to start making complicated things on Ansible!
I started to rewrite my Puppet manifests to Ansible playbooks and what I can say is it&amp;rsquo;s really fast and easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickly search in your logs with Elasticsearch, Kibana and Fluentd</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/09/quickly-search-in-your-logs-with-elasticsearch-kibana-and-fluentd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/09/quickly-search-in-your-logs-with-elasticsearch-kibana-and-fluentd/</guid>
      <description>Managing logs is not a complicated tasks with classical syslog systems (syslog-ng, rsyslog&amp;hellip;). However, being able to search in them quickly when you have several gigabit of logs, with scalability, with a nice graphical interface etc&amp;hellip;is not the same thing.
Hopefully today, tools that permit to do it very well exists, here are the list of tools that&amp;rsquo;s we&amp;rsquo;re going to use to achieve it:
 Elasticsearch: Elasticsearch is a flexible and powerful open source, distributed, real-time search and analytics engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mysqlnd: replace your old php mysql client library by mysqlnd</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/05/mysqlnd-replace-your-php-mysql-library-libmysqlclient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/05/mysqlnd-replace-your-php-mysql-library-libmysqlclient/</guid>
      <description>As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;m using and loving MariaDB. A colleague recently introduced me the benefits of the php built-in MySQL/MariaDB library (shame on me, I never heard of it). Here are the informations you can find from it on the MySQL website:
 The mysqlnd library is highly optimized for and tightly integrated into PHP. The MySQL Client Library cannot offer the same optimizations because it is a general-purpose client library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data meetup with Twitter feedbacks</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/03/big-data-meetup-with-twitter-feedbacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/03/big-data-meetup-with-twitter-feedbacks/</guid>
      <description>On next Monday, a meetup will take place in Paris concerning Big Data with Twitter feeback. This meetup will be live retransmitted through YouTube.
The main talk will speak about how Twitter did to scale to millions of users:
 Twitter is one of the most heavily trafficked sites on the internet, with over 240 million active users and serving over 500 million Tweets per day. Twitter, as a company and as a service has seen remarkable growth in its eight years of existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seafile: try a self hosted Dropbox like</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/01/seafile-try-a-self-hosted-dropbox-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/01/seafile-try-a-self-hosted-dropbox-like/</guid>
      <description>My last post was about existing alternatives to Dropbox. I also mentioned that I was trying Seafile.
I&amp;rsquo;m running now Seafile since a few days now and it works without any issues. The Linux and Android clients works very well. I just hope a sync feature in the Android version will appear. Regarding the web version, there are all attending collaboration features and that&amp;rsquo;s great. Seafile supports file versioning and trash bin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRM: automatic MySQL/MariaDB replication managment</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/25/prm-automatic-mysqlmariadb-replication-managment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/25/prm-automatic-mysqlmariadb-replication-managment/</guid>
      <description>The Percona replication manager (PRM) is a framework using the Linux HA resource agent Pacemaker that manages replication and provides automatic failover. This covers the installation of the framework on a set of servers. The PRM framework is made of 4 components: Corosync, Pacemaker, the mysql resource agent and MySQL itself.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to setup, better if you already know how to use Pacemaker and it works like a charm. In fact it setup a master and x slaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monit: easily use triggers on your system</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/23/monit-easily-use-triggers-on-your-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/23/monit-easily-use-triggers-on-your-system/</guid>
      <description>monit is a utility for managing and monitoring processes, programs, files, directories and filesystems on a Unix system. Monit conducts automatic maintenance and repair and can execute meaningful causal actions in error situations. E.g. Monit can start a process if it does not run, restart a process if it does not respond and stop a process if it uses too much resources. You can use Monit to monitor files, directories and filesystems for changes, such as timestamps changes, checksum changes or size changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i3block: alternative status bar for i3 &#43; my contributions</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/21/i3block-alternative-status-bar-for-i3-my-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 10:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/21/i3block-alternative-status-bar-for-i3-my-contributions/</guid>
      <description>You know that I recently switched to i3. One of the first thing I wanted to change is the status bar which is not optimal for my usage.
After researches, it looked like that i3blocks it the best alternative. So I contacted the creator (Vivien) and had very good exchanges with him.
I&amp;rsquo;ve made pull requests and suggestions to integrate missing checks, faster one that I developed and with colorization depending of the contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZNC: install and configure an IRC bouncer</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/19/znc-install-and-configure-an-irc-bouncer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/19/znc-install-and-configure-an-irc-bouncer/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to install an IRC bouncer as I was fed up to launch every say a ssh to connect to an external server, on which I had a tmux running a weechat to get IRC history. 2 problems here:
 Sometimes, I forgot to connect on it and missed some messages It was not integrated to Pidgin (what I use for any IM protocol)  So I decided to setup a bounce IRC with ZNC!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAXSI: Add security to your Nginx</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/15/naxsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/15/naxsi/</guid>
      <description>NAXSI means Nginx Anti Xss &amp;amp; Sql Injection. Technically, it is a third party nginx module, available as a package for many UNIX-like platforms. This module, by default, reads a small subset of simple rules (naxsi_core.rules) containing 99% of known patterns involved in websites vulnerabilities. For example, &amp;lsquo;&amp;lt; &amp;lsquo;, &amp;lsquo;|&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;drop&amp;rsquo; are not supposed to be part of a URI.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while that I wanted to test NAXSI and it seams working not so bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceph: why don’t you try Ceph and stop disks array?</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/11/ceph-why-dont-you-try-ceph-and-stop-disks-array/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/11/ceph-why-dont-you-try-ceph-and-stop-disks-array/</guid>
      <description>In France, we have the chance to have an ISP/Mobile Telephony provider called Free. They considerably reduced the market price for the Mobile phone communications in 2012. This was very fine for competition and for French people. Now we can have correct prices for Internet and cell phone data. Thanks to Free.
Ceph is quite the same as Free but for storage systems. Since many years, disks array constructors sold us locked solutions with a very high cost of hardware and licenses&amp;rsquo; software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL: diagnose and correct the heartbleed issue</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/08/openssl-diagnose-and-correct-the-heartbleed-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/08/openssl-diagnose-and-correct-the-heartbleed-issue/</guid>
      <description>A big and major issue on OpenSSL has been discovered and everybody is talking about it. To get more informations, there&amp;rsquo;s a website.
How to check the vulnerability, download this file:
chmod 755 ssltest.py  Now launch it:
./ssltest.py blog.deimos.fr Connecting... Sending Client Hello... Waiting for Server Hello... ... received message: type = 22, ver = 0302, length = 66 ... received message: type = 22, ver = 0302, length = 5559 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I finally switched from Awesome to i3</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/07/i-finally-switched-from-awesome-to-i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/07/i-finally-switched-from-awesome-to-i3/</guid>
      <description>Yes once again and for a long time now I think, I moved to i3. It does not make so many thing than Awesome, however working on multiple screen with it, it&amp;rsquo;s better.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I wanted to make a new test with it and it&amp;rsquo;s now adopted. I spent a little bit time on reconfiguring all my needs (workspaces depending my screen configuration, opening app on a defined workspace, keyboard bindings etc&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ccze: easily colorize your logs output</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/28/eccza-easily-colorize-your-logs-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/28/eccza-easily-colorize-your-logs-output/</guid>
      <description>Some of you will tell me that most utility is doing it as well. And that&amp;rsquo;s right, but with ccze you will be able to colorize everything with a pipe. For example when you play with a verbose service like Pacemaker, you need to get colorization if you want to win time. Here is an example:
tail -f /var/log/syslog | ccze -A  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postfix: hold outgoing mail transport</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/20/postfix-hold-outgoing-mail-transport/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 11:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/20/postfix-hold-outgoing-mail-transport/</guid>
      <description>When you manage Postfix and have a trouble with your mail infrastructure, you may want to set in maintenance your Postfix without loosing any mails. Here is a way to hold the queue, giving the time to analyze the problem and then release the queue.
I&amp;rsquo;ve wrote some tips on it. I hope it will help you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packer: win time by easily testing your app on multiple platforms</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/18/packer-win-time-by-easily-testing-your-app-on-multiple-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 11:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/18/packer-win-time-by-easily-testing-your-app-on-multiple-platforms/</guid>
      <description>Packer is a tool for creating identical machine images for multiple platforms from a single source configuration. You can win a lot of time by testing your application on multiple environments (AWS, OpenStack, VirtualBox, Vmware&amp;hellip;).
Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;ve got a LAMP environment to deploy in production on OpenStack. However, you can&amp;rsquo;t perform your development/integration on it as you don&amp;rsquo;t have access yet. You can&amp;rsquo;t loose time and wait for it to test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postfix: limit outgoing mail throttling</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/14/postfix-limit-outgoing-mail-throttling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 11:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/14/postfix-limit-outgoing-mail-throttling/</guid>
      <description>When you have a huge amount of mail to deliver, you can&amp;rsquo;t release the queue at once and let the server maximize the outgoing mail throughput ! The result will be: you&amp;rsquo;ll get blacklisted from a lot of MX servers.
That&amp;rsquo;s why you should take care of it and do traffic shaping. I&amp;rsquo;ve wrote a little tips on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant: 2 super cool new features in V1.5</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/12/vagrant-v1-5-use-boxes-on-vagrantcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/12/vagrant-v1-5-use-boxes-on-vagrantcloud/</guid>
      <description>The 1.5 version of Vagrant has been released and that&amp;rsquo;s awesome ! They finally did a Cloud where all Vagrant boxes could (https://vagrantcloud.com/) be inventoried and easily deployed through command line !
You can find my boxes here. If you want to add one, it&amp;rsquo;s really simple:
vagrant box add deimosfr/debian-wheezy  And the second awesome feature is&amp;hellip;the sharing! You can for example have access to a distant and nated Vagrant instance through SSH!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HAProxy: a powerful load balancer</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/10/haproxy-a-powerful-load-balancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/10/haproxy-a-powerful-load-balancer/</guid>
      <description>I recently played with HAProxy and discovered that I&amp;rsquo;ve never made a documentation regarding this fantastic software. So if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what HAProxy is, it&amp;rsquo;s a load balancer working on layer 7 and specialized for http protocol.
It is able to handle sticky sessions which is really powerful. More than that, it has a small footprint and can work under a high load traffic.
Here is my documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: the Puppet outsider!</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/04/ansible-the-puppet-outsider/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 11:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/04/ansible-the-puppet-outsider/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while now that I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of Ansible but I only started playing with a week ago. You may certainly know that I&amp;rsquo;m a Puppet lover, but this solution is more powerful than Puppet in my opinion.
So I started to migrate my personal Puppet to Ansible just to play with. Here are the pros:
 No client needed on the clients, only SSH! It&amp;rsquo;s written in Python By default a lot of modules Not only a configuration management tool, it&amp;rsquo;s an orchestrator too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant: do not manage VBox Guest Additions manually anymore</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/28/vagrant-do-not-manage-vbox-guest-additions-manually-anymore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/28/vagrant-do-not-manage-vbox-guest-additions-manually-anymore/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered a Vagrant plugin that manage the VirtualBox Guest Additions automatically. I mean, when you launch a virtual machine, it automatically checks if the Guest Additions are installed. If it&amp;rsquo;s not the case or if they are not up to date, installation of the latest version is made automatically !
Here is how to install it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux: better fonts for Retina display</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/24/linux-better-fonts-for-retina-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/24/linux-better-fonts-for-retina-display/</guid>
      <description>Big resolution with small screens is more and more common and we&amp;rsquo;re facing a problem on fonts visualization as the readability is not optimal. We have a lot of non adapted fonts for retina display, even if most of them are not so bad. The solution to resolve that problem is to install additional fonts to replace the default one. And one of the best one I&amp;rsquo;ve seen is Infinality fonts !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PageSpeed disable Varnish by default ! Get both working together</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/20/pagespeed-disable-varnish-by-default-get-both-working-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/20/pagespeed-disable-varnish-by-default-get-both-working-together/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday a colleague (Dimitri) tested a tool on this blog. He informed me that Varnish was disabled and PageSpeed may be the cause as this is the last modification I&amp;rsquo;ve made on the server.
After verification he was totally right ! By default, PageSpeed disable cache by serving HTML files with:
Cache-Control: no-cache, max-age=0  After reading the PageSpeed documentation on that topic, it is clear: PageSpeed needs to know how to purge the cache as it rewrites a lot of elements and it has the control instead of the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deimos.fr is now using PageSpeed :-)…feedbacks</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/16/deimos-fr-is-now-using-pagespeed-feedbacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 11:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/16/deimos-fr-is-now-using-pagespeed-feedbacks/</guid>
      <description>Following a previous post, I&amp;rsquo;ve enabled PageSpeed on both wiki and blog deimos.fr.
What I can say is, it&amp;rsquo;s very important to take the time to test every optimizations you want to add. I experienced for example issues on silly things like :
# Optimize browser rendering pagespeed EnableFilters lazyload_images;  Some images weren&amp;rsquo;t shown if you didn&amp;rsquo;t refresh once again your page browser. I only had this problem on the blog and not the wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page Speed: optimize on the fly your rendered code with Nginx</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/12/page-speed-optimize-on-the-fly-your-rendered-code-with-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/12/page-speed-optimize-on-the-fly-your-rendered-code-with-nginx/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve first heard of Page Speed last year for Apache. I was really waiting a stable version for Nginx and it&amp;rsquo;s now done. A few days ago, Nicolargo made a post regarding it and that&amp;rsquo;s what motivated me to go ahead on Page Speed.
PageSpeed speeds up your site and reduces page load time. This open-source webserver module automatically applies web performance best practices to pages and associated assets (CSS, JavaScript, images) without requiring that you modify your existing content or workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dotdeb: Use up to date packages for the web</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/10/detdeb-use-up-to-date-packages-for-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/02/10/detdeb-use-up-to-date-packages-for-the-web/</guid>
      <description>I discovered Dotdeb a few months ago and decided to make a quick documentation to install the repository. But before, here is the official explaination of what is the repository made for :
 Dotdeb is a repository containing packages to turn your Debian boxes into powerful, stable and up-to-date LAMP servers :
 Nginx PHP 5.4 and 5.3, useful PHP extensions : APC, imagick, Pinba, xcache, Xdebug, XHprof… MySQL 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News in bulk</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/25/news-in-bulk-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/25/news-in-bulk-3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated some of my tutorials :
 Optimizing Hard Drive performances : I&amp;rsquo;ve updated SSD subject Luks : added more information on how auto mount automatically at boot a crypted partition. Xtrabackup : corrected a non working command LXC : modified containers files to avoid boot issues APT-Pinning : Added the command to install a package from a designed repository Sed : forgotten to add -i option which is so important Vagrant : Added an example to the quick tutorial  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offloading SSL with Nginx and Varnish</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/23/offloading-ssl-with-nginx-and-varnish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/23/offloading-ssl-with-nginx-and-varnish/</guid>
      <description>Varnish is a real powerful cache solution for web servers. He is unfortunately not able to do it over SSL. Anyway, there is a solution by offloading it with Nginx. Here is a schema to get a better understanding :
Nginx decrypt SSL, pass it in clear to Varnish. If Varnish got it, replies to Nginx which crypt back data to send to user.
I&amp;rsquo;ve made a full documentation to get it working well, follow the link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceph: setup Rados Block Devices (RBD) nodes on Debian</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/21/ceph-setup-block-devices-rbd-nodes-on-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/21/ceph-setup-block-devices-rbd-nodes-on-debian/</guid>
      <description>In addition of object storage, Ceph is able to provide block devices. Ceph’s RADOS Block Device (RBD) provides access to block device images that are striped and replicated across the entire storage cluster.
For example this is used to store Virtual Machines on OpenStack. With that solution, you&amp;rsquo;ve got a real fault tolerance system for your VM and distributed.
The RBD part is an easy task when you&amp;rsquo;ve already setup a Ceph cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CloudFlare : testing a free CDN</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/17/cloudflare-testing-a-free-cdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/17/cloudflare-testing-a-free-cdn/</guid>
      <description>CloudFlare is a Free solution to load your website faster and add security. I&amp;rsquo;ve tested it 2 days ago, that&amp;rsquo;s why you may experienced issues in accessing the blog and wiki.
I had issues on WordPress, so I need to correct some problems relating images (http/https) as the Free version of CloudFlare doesn&amp;rsquo;t support SSL. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;ve roll back for the moment.
I have other kind of modifications to make on WordPress before it works as it should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceph: setup Objects Storage (OSD) nodes on Debian</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/15/ceph-setup-objects-storage-osd-nodes-on-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 11:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/15/ceph-setup-objects-storage-osd-nodes-on-debian/</guid>
      <description>Following the previous post, on Ceph Storage, I&amp;rsquo;ve updated my documentation with informations to play with OSD. I&amp;rsquo;ve covered :
 Setup OSD Remove OSD Use Ceph Ojects Storage  Using the object storage system is not complicated and easily scalable. It&amp;rsquo;s a real pleasure to work with that kind of solutions. If you&amp;rsquo;re already working with other objects storage solutions, you won&amp;rsquo;t be lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceph: setup Monitors nodes (mon) on Debian</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/13/ceph-installation-and-configuration-on-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 11:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/13/ceph-installation-and-configuration-on-debian/</guid>
      <description>I finally started to play with Ceph to add it in production. I&amp;rsquo;m still impressed by this storage solution. Just to remind, Ceph is an open-source, massively scalable, software-defined storage system which provides object, block and file system storage (not yet ready for production usage) in a single platform. It runs on commodity hardware-saving you costs, giving you flexibility. And as it’s in the Linux kernel, it’s easy to consume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage cgroups with cgconfig on Debian</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/09/manage-cgroups-with-cgconfig-on-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 11:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/09/manage-cgroups-with-cgconfig-on-debian/</guid>
      <description>Cgroups permit to restrict a process to specific hardware like CPU or limiting IO disk etc&amp;hellip; Managing it manually could be a nightmare and hopefully, a good workaround exists.
It&amp;rsquo;s called cgconfig and allows you to have a running daemon to apply restrictions on all new running process. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a documentation for it and spent time on it as it&amp;rsquo;s not properly Debian packaged yet :-(</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx : set your site in maintenance easily</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/26/nginx-set-your-site-in-maintenance-easily/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/26/nginx-set-your-site-in-maintenance-easily/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to set a website in maintenance and wanted to do it as quickly as possible with any restart of Nginx.
The idea is to add a maintenance.html page at the root of your web folder and then the maintenance page is automatically taken into account.
To do it, simply follow the link (in french).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP-FPM : get status information page for monitoring</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/22/php-fpm-get-status-information-page-for-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/22/php-fpm-get-status-information-page-for-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>To be able to monitor the PHP-FPM service with connections, queue information, process&amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ll need to set the status page. This will give you something like this :
pool: www process manager: dynamic start time: 18/Dec/2013:19:00:41 +0100 start since: 52972 accepted conn: 5268 listen queue: 0 max listen queue: 0 listen queue len: 0 idle processes: 3 active processes: 1 total processes: 4 max active processes: 4 max children reached: 0  Those informations are important to correctly tune the PHP-FPM service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first Vagrant box is Debian Wheezy</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/20/my-first-vagrant-box-is-debian-wheezy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 11:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/20/my-first-vagrant-box-is-debian-wheezy/</guid>
      <description>If you follow me, you should be aware that I use Vagrant every day. I wanted to get a Wheezy version with fr keyboard, up to date, correct locales and configured source.list file. I&amp;rsquo;ve also added Puppet and Chef on it.
So I&amp;rsquo;ve learned on how to build a box and it&amp;rsquo;s really easy by following the documentations on the website. Here is my Debian Wheezy box based on VirtualBox provider available on DropBox or Mega.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx : add more security to your SSL</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/16/nginx-add-more-security-to-your-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/16/nginx-add-more-security-to-your-ssl/</guid>
      <description>In those time, security is more and more important. Some vulnerabilities have been discovered and security on your SSL should be added. In fact you need to restrict the possibilities to your SSL server to avoid SSL breaks.
I&amp;rsquo;ve updated my documentation to add SSL Resumption and authorized ciphers algorithms.
Then you can check your SSL server security here : https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/index.html.
I hope this will help you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant : one file generate several machines</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/14/vagrant-one-file-generate-several-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/14/vagrant-one-file-generate-several-machines/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently playing with Ceph and wanted to generate multiple machines (6) on my laptop to perform several tests. I needed :
 1 public network 1 private network Debian wheezy OS Automatically install Ceph Add disk for specific machines (OSD)  It wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy to make it work quickly as the documentation doesn&amp;rsquo;t give a lot of examples. But what a powerful solution when it works !
If you want to try multiple VM managment, please follow the link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update 2 : Debian on the 11,1 model MacBook Pro 13</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/08/update-2-debian-on-the-111-model-macbook-pro-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 11:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/08/update-2-debian-on-the-111-model-macbook-pro-13/</guid>
      <description>I think this will be the last post for the Debian installation on MacBook Pro 13&amp;rsquo; late 2013. To resume, here are the previous posts :
 http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/10/27/debian-on-the-last-macbook-pro-13/ http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/10/update-1-debian-on-the-111-model-macbook-pro-13/  The majority of the bugs will be resolve in the Linux Kernel 3.13. I&amp;rsquo;ve tested the rc2, but it&amp;rsquo;s too much unstable for the moment and I need to wait. Arch wiki gives a lot of informations to make (most of) everything working :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mdadm : create a raid 1</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/06/mdadm-create-a-raid-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/06/mdadm-create-a-raid-1/</guid>
      <description>I recently added RAID 1 on my mac mini under Debian. I used mdadm and remembered how easy it is.
I&amp;rsquo;ve added some updates to my documentation to create a RAID without waiting a full sync.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC : my documentation finally finished</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/30/lxc-my-documentation-finally-finished/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/30/lxc-my-documentation-finally-finished/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally finished my documentation on LXC for Debian Wheezy. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve added the most interesting features.
I&amp;rsquo;m now going to migrate my servers from KVM to LXC as I only POC it for now. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you up to date when everything will be migrated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC : use dnsmasq instead of libvirt</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/28/lxc-use-dnsmasq-instead-of-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/28/lxc-use-dnsmasq-instead-of-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>LXC is a really good container solution to replace older container solutions like OpenVZ or Vserver for instance. Libvirt is a wonderful tool to manage different hypervisors and containers solutions. Anyway Libvirt is unfortunately not able to fully manage LXC (create, delete&amp;hellip;) today.
That&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary to get it running and installed on a server, but it could be useful if you have KVM and LXC working on the same machine to get the same tool to handle start/stop containers/VMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iptables is going to be replaced by NFtables</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/24/iptables-is-going-to-be-replaced-by-nftables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 11:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/24/iptables-is-going-to-be-replaced-by-nftables/</guid>
      <description>If you’re not aware that the next kernel version will replace iptables by nftables, it’s time to learn on how it works, what are the features, why the change and how to use it.
If like me, you love PF, you&amp;rsquo;ll be pleased to find a similar syntax on NFtables ! To have a good introduction on it, look at those slides :
  Kernel Recipes 2013 - Nftables, what motivations and what solutions  from Anne Nicolas</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News in bulk</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/12/news-in-bulk-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2013 11:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/12/news-in-bulk-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated some of my tutorials :
Stress : CPU test usage
Firefox Sync Server : upgrade procedure updated
AutoFS : adding FTP (curlfs)
Kernel compilation : updated with the latest compression format
PuppetDB : updated to work with the latest PuppetDB version
SSH : how to change your ssh key passphrase</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redshift : screen color temperature adjuster</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/06/redshift-screen-color-temperature-adjuster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 11:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/06/redshift-screen-color-temperature-adjuster/</guid>
      <description>Redshift adjusts the color temperature of your screen according to your surroundings. This may help your eyes hurt less if you are working in front of the screen at night.
Two of my colleagues (Julien and Axel) praise virtues of this application. So I started to use it yesterday. For the moment, my opinion is good during the night, but during the day&amp;hellip;I don&amp;rsquo;t have opinion for the moment.
Here is my configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yubikey : debug your authentication problems</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/04/yubikey-debug-your-authentication-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 11:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/11/04/yubikey-debug-your-authentication-problems/</guid>
      <description>Since I&amp;rsquo;ve reinstalled my desktop on my new MacBook Pro 13, I had to fight with some problems with my Yubikey. I never had such and wonder if it couldn&amp;rsquo;t comes from a Debian package update.
Anyway, I had problem with permissions on the USB device and found a udev solution. I&amp;rsquo;ve updated my documentation and let you check and would like a feedback if some of you have encountered the same issue (USB error: Access denied (insufficient permissions))</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LUKS and Yubikey for crypted boot</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/10/29/change-luks-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/10/29/change-luks-password/</guid>
      <description>I recently crypted all my disk as I changed laptop. At the beginning, I just tested a simple password to see performances changes.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t really see changes for the moment.
Once I&amp;rsquo;ve finished to install and configure my needs, I wanted to have a strong password solution. I decided to use a remembered password concatenated to a generated yubikey password.
I updated my LUKS tutorial to explain how to update the password.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian on the 11,1 model MacBook Pro 13</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/10/27/debian-on-the-last-macbook-pro-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 11:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/10/27/debian-on-the-last-macbook-pro-13/</guid>
      <description>I tested to install Debian as I love it more than Mac OS X for work on my new MacBook Pro 13 retina. Most of the hardware works out of the box on a Debian Jessie (because of the kernel version &amp;gt; 3.8) but is not really optimal. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain how I did to make it better.
First of all, you need an EFI manager. I discovered that Refit is not maintained anymore and let place to rEFInd instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell : back to directory command (bd)</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/09/19/shell-back-to-directory-command-bd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 10:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/09/19/shell-back-to-directory-command-bd/</guid>
      <description>I recently read a post (on Korben&amp;rsquo;s blog) regarding a command called bd to go back to a directory from you current full path. It permits to do more than that !
In fact this is a simple shell script, but it really helps when you&amp;rsquo;re in a long subfolder list. For example if you reside in &amp;lsquo;/home/user/project/src/org/main/site/utils/file/reader/whatever&amp;rsquo; and want to change to &amp;lsquo;/home/user/project/test&amp;rsquo;, then try &amp;lsquo;bd p`/test.
If you want to see all the possibilities, you can look at the main site project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pootle : simple translation tool</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/09/17/pootle-simple-translation-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/09/17/pootle-simple-translation-tool/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to install a simple translation tool that helps on follow the translation activity of a project. Pootle answered my requests very well and that&amp;rsquo;s why I created a documentation to deploy it. It&amp;rsquo;s written in Python and use Django.
Here is my Pootle tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC : how to convert a host/vm to a container</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/09/11/lxc-how-to-convert-a-hostvm-to-a-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/09/11/lxc-how-to-convert-a-hostvm-to-a-container/</guid>
      <description>As you can see, I write more and more posts on LXC. The latest thing I worked on, was how to convert a host/vm to a LXC container. I needed to write a script for it as I didn&amp;rsquo;t find what I needed.
The script will remove unneeded elements in a Debian system, removing folders (dev,proc,sys), recreate devices and configure etc files. You can find more informations by following the link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRBD : advanced usages</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/09/09/drbd-advanced-usages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/09/09/drbd-advanced-usages/</guid>
      <description>At my work, I taught a DRBD training for advanced usages at work. I produced some slides and I would like to share them :
 I hope it could help&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome : autostart app on boot depending on connected screens</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/09/01/awesome-autostart-app-on-boot-depending-on-connected-screens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 10:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/09/01/awesome-autostart-app-on-boot-depending-on-connected-screens/</guid>
      <description>Awesome is still my window manager and I still love it. With my laptop, I need to be able to quickly get my working environment when I power it on. The major problem I had was to avoid having the same opened windows at boot if I&amp;rsquo;m in the train, at work or at home. Of course there is no GPS in the laptop to detect my location, so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t set a rule for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppet: start to write your own module</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/30/puppet-start-to-write-your-own-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/30/puppet-start-to-write-your-own-module/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t really play with Puppet since a long time and a lot of things have changed.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently writing a Puppet module for MySecureShell. And the thing is, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to quickly find the relevant information on how to build a module from scratch. I like to have experience return and what a chance when I saw a tweet regarding it, the same day as I started to write the module :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC : Some little setbacks</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/28/some-little-setbacks-with-lxc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/28/some-little-setbacks-with-lxc/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;m new to LXC, I am discovering how it works, see the maturity of the project and it&amp;rsquo;s integration in Debian. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a post a few weeks ago to introduce the basics and now I&amp;rsquo;m digging in advanced features.
I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered several issues. Most of them are not critical but unfortunately looks like a lack of integration on Debian.
 The first one is related to wheezy template and I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about it in a previous post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dotdeb : get the latest packages for your Debian stable</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/24/dotdeb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 10:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/24/dotdeb/</guid>
      <description>I recently discovered that repository that looks correctly maintained and often updated.
I like this repository as it&amp;rsquo;s updated faster than the Debian one and you can have the latest version of some packages. Of course you can do package pinning if you only want one or a set of packages.
You can access to the repository here : http://www.dotdeb.org/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glances : all in one monitoring shell tool</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/22/glances-all-in-one-monitoring-shell-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 10:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/22/glances-all-in-one-monitoring-shell-tool/</guid>
      <description>Glances is a cross-platform curses-based monitoring tool written in Python.
It avoids to run several tools to get a all in one overview of your system. For example, when you want to quickly see what&amp;rsquo;s wrong on a system for diagnosis, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to launch top/htop, iostat, vmstat&amp;hellip;Glances gives you a large overview of your system health.
You can then investigate with the appropriate tool if you want. But you didn&amp;rsquo;t waste your time in opening several tools to get the first desired information : where does the problem comes from ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install and configure a monitoring machine for a supervision screen</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/20/how-to-install-and-configure-a-monitoring-machine-for-supervision/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/20/how-to-install-and-configure-a-monitoring-machine-for-supervision/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this documentation is how to quickly setup a monitoring screen machine for Nagios/Shinken. Several times in several company I had to do that kind of thing. On Mac OS and Linux.
I finished to create a documentation for the next times I&amp;rsquo;ll have to deploy such things. The idea is to have a machine that nobody never touch once installed. It&amp;rsquo;s always boring to plug a keyboard and a mouse when somethings goes wrong on this kind of machine that you normally never have to touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beamer : my quick tutorial to write LaTeX presentations</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/16/beamer-my-quick-tutorial-to-write-latex-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/16/beamer-my-quick-tutorial-to-write-latex-presentations/</guid>
      <description>This is not my first post on Beamer and not the first time I say I really like this piece of software.
As for LaTeX&amp;rsquo;s newbies it&amp;rsquo;s not really easy to start Beamer and as many people liked my last slides on MariaDB/MySQL. More than that, I had to make a presentation on DRBD at work and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to write it with Beamer.
My colleagues appreciated the look and LaTeX format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MediaWiki/Sphinx : setup a full text indexer</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/12/mediawikisphinx-setup-a-full-text-indexer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 10:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/12/mediawikisphinx-setup-a-full-text-indexer/</guid>
      <description>You certainly know and have used the default MediaWiki search. It&amp;rsquo;s quite good but it&amp;rsquo;s not an optimal search. I wanted to have better one for my wiki that&amp;rsquo;s why I added Google search some years ago.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to setup Apache Lucene or Apache Solar as both are in Java. I always heard good feedback about Sphinx, that&amp;rsquo;s why I decided to add it at work and to my wiki as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PackStack : quickly deploy OpenStack for production</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/08/packstack-quickly-deploy-openstack-for-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/08/packstack-quickly-deploy-openstack-for-production/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I&amp;rsquo;ve assisted to a webinar organized by Puppet Labs. The talk was about PackStack which is a solution to deploy OpenStack in a production environment.
How does PackStack works ? Some of you may tell me that DevStack do the same thing. But I warn once again about DevStack which is absolutely not build for production usages ! PackStack is a bundle of current modules for OpenStack available on Puppet Forge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PuPHPet : speed up your Vagrant deployment</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/06/puphpet-speed-up-your-vagrant-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/06/puphpet-speed-up-your-vagrant-deployment/</guid>
      <description>Vagrant is a fast solution build on top of VirtualBox. I already talked about it in a previous post.
The thing is, you could do really more with Vagrant by adding Puppet manifests or Chef recipes in your Vagrant configuration file. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t often use one of those 2 softwares, it quickly could transform into a nightmare when they want to deploy softwares in addition of the OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you want to try my desktop configuration ?</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/04/do-you-want-to-try-my-dektop-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 10:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/04/do-you-want-to-try-my-dektop-configuration/</guid>
      <description>Some of you already told me how complicated the setup of my software configurations could be. Depending on which configuration you&amp;rsquo;re talking about, it may be more or less complicated to install in the good folders, launching the good commands etc&amp;hellip;
In addition, sometimes I need to set up a quick desktop environment with my preferences and deploy all I need may take a while. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;ve written some scripts (in Python and shell script) to help on deploying all my configuration and all the packages I wish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC : Debian reported issue still not fixed</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/02/lxc-debian-reported-issue-still-not-fixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/02/lxc-debian-reported-issue-still-not-fixed/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone ! As you know I recently started to play with LXC :-)
At the beginning of my tests, I unfortunately found an annoying bug which avoid performing correct Debian installation over LVM.
I tried to resolve it by myself but didn&amp;rsquo;t had enough time to finish my investigation. After quick searches, I found that other people found the bug on github : https://github.com/simonvanderveldt/lxc-debian-wheezy-template/issues/1#issuecomment-21303483
As a rule, I searched it on Debian bugs list but nothing was reported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book : Pro Git</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/21/book-pro-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/21/book-pro-git/</guid>
      <description>Git : have you ever tried to play with it ? For several years I&amp;rsquo;m working with that fantastic tool. Anyway the biggest problem is : if you don&amp;rsquo;t work day to day with Git, you need a memento or something similar (like my wiki 😉).
Also, if you use it for your personal usage, you&amp;rsquo;ll be lost when you will work with complex workflows. As I&amp;rsquo;m not a developer, I use Git to manage my etc configuration, my puppet manifests, my custom scripts&amp;hellip;so many basic usage that really help me to win time as a sysadmin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC : basic installation and usage</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/17/lxc-basic-installation-and-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/17/lxc-basic-installation-and-usage/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I started to play with LXC. It is the userspace control package for Linux Containers, a lightweight virtual system mechanism sometimes described as “chroot on steroids”.
LXC builds up from chroot to implement complete virtual systems, adding resource management and isolation mechanisms to Linux’s existing process management infrastructure.
I wanted to look at an alternative of OpenVZ and LXC seams to be the better solution. That&amp;rsquo;s why I started to play with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRBD : how to recover failed synchronisation</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/13/drbd-how-to-recover-failed-synchronisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/13/drbd-how-to-recover-failed-synchronisation/</guid>
      <description>DRBD is an old stable solution to create block disk replications over the network. However in some case, we need to deal with failures for several reasons (hardware, network issues&amp;hellip;).
I&amp;rsquo;ve updated my current documentation on this point and hope this will help some of you. You can find the update here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yubikey : protect your desktop authentication using pam and yubikey library</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/09/yubikey-protect-your-desktop-authentication-using-pam-and-yubikey-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/09/yubikey-protect-your-desktop-authentication-using-pam-and-yubikey-library/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve bought 2 Yubikeys several months ago and didn&amp;rsquo;t really took the time to play with them.
A ex-colleague took that time and configured it on his desktop under ArchLinux. I decided to play with it, see how could it works and with his help, put it in place in a very short time.
I configured it to work in parallel of my password. With that configuration, I do not need anymore typing my password, but only need to plug in my Yubikey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use old Debian repository for unmaintained Debian versions</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/07/how-to-use-old-debian-repository-for-unmaintained-debian-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 10:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/07/how-to-use-old-debian-repository-for-unmaintained-debian-versions/</guid>
      <description>Installing old Debian to prepare a migration is quite good when repositories are still available. But for old unmaintained versions of Debian, we need to change some things.
Hopefully Debian still keep all the old versions in an archive repository that is accessible by changing the default url. Even if during install it fails, you can set it up afterward.
I&amp;rsquo;ve wrote a little article on it, follow the link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My slim theme</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/29/my-slim-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/29/my-slim-theme/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m using Slim for a few months and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with it. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, do what does it have to do and it&amp;rsquo;s light. But I wanted to customize it to give a look similar to my Awesome theme.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;ve took Gimp and modified a theme I liked. You can see the result :-)
You can find my configuration here and modify it if you want :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MariaDB/MySQL slides for HA and performances tuning</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/21/mariadbmysql-slides-for-ha-and-performances-tuning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/21/mariadbmysql-slides-for-ha-and-performances-tuning/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave a training on MariaDB/MySQL regarding performances tuning and High Availability. You can find here the slides I&amp;rsquo;ve made for it (french).
Some subjects related in that document are replication master -&amp;gt; slave, master &amp;lt; -&amp;gt; master and Galera Cluster. You can download the PDF here or see it directly on SlideShare :
I hope this will help some of you to get a better understanding on some advanced features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selfoss : An elegant RSS reader</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/19/3508/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 10:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/19/3508/</guid>
      <description>Selfoss is a self-hosted RSS reader solution. It could be compared to Tiny Tiny RSS or Feedly.
I liked to test that nice solution. But I&amp;rsquo;m still staying with Fever, as there is no Android version working with Selfoss (only an old one exist, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t work) and the web interface is a little bit slow (compared to Fever). I hope this will be better in a short term as this is the most elegant Open Source version I&amp;rsquo;ve tested for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox Sync : build your own sync server</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/03/firefox-sync-build-your-own-sync-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/03/firefox-sync-build-your-own-sync-server/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m very happy of Mozilla Sync service and trust more in Mozilla foundation than Google for my datas. Anyway there is a thing that I don&amp;rsquo;t like : sharing my passwords into the cloud !
That&amp;rsquo;s why I decided to create my own Sync Server. I want to thanks Mozilla for their work, it works like a charm :-). So now I don&amp;rsquo;t use Mozilla server anymore, but my own. Here is the documentation on how I did that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switch audio output to another USB device</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/01/swith-audio-output-to-another-usb-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 10:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/01/swith-audio-output-to-another-usb-device/</guid>
      <description>I recently talked about my new keyboard and the output sound directly on the keyboard. That&amp;rsquo;s a great thing, but depending on your distribution and the desktop you&amp;rsquo;ve installed, it may not work out of the box.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;ve written a documentation to make it work.
In addition, I&amp;rsquo;ve modified my awesome configuration to get special music keys to work like a charm :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrit : Add an integrity control tool on your Debian</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/26/integrit-add-an-integrity-control-tool-on-your-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/26/integrit-add-an-integrity-control-tool-on-your-debian/</guid>
      <description>Integrit is a simple yet secure alternative to products like tripwire. It has a small memory footprint, uses up-to-date cryptographic algorithms, and has features that make sense (like including the MD5 checksum of newly generated databases in the report.
You may already now the alternatives on OpenBSD or RedHat. So now let&amp;rsquo;s play with Debian :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weechat : a user friendly IRC client</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/24/weechat-a-user-friendly-irc-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 10:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/24/weechat-a-user-friendly-irc-client/</guid>
      <description>WeeChat is a fast, light and extensible chat client. It runs on many platforms (including Linux, BSD and Mac OS). I&amp;rsquo;m using it over a year and really love that client.
WeeChat is:
 modular: a lightweight core with plugins around multi-protocols: IRC and Jabber (other soon) extensible: C plugins and scripts (Perl, Python, Ruby, Lua, Tcl and Scheme) free software: released under GPLv3 license fully documented: user&amp;rsquo;s guide, API, FAQ,.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulate a black hole for a domain with Postfix</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/20/simulate-a-black-hole-for-a-domain-with-postfix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 10:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/20/simulate-a-black-hole-for-a-domain-with-postfix/</guid>
      <description>When you manage outgoing emails through SMTP, you may sometimes need to test if a service is able to send correctly emails and itself check that there were no issue during sending. You can create a black hole for a specific domain and Postfix will answer from the same manner as if it is ok. It also permit to test Postfix sending capacities on a server.
To get more informations on this, follow that link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cpulimit : limit CPU usage</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/18/cpulimit-limit-cpu-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/18/cpulimit-limit-cpu-usage/</guid>
      <description>In a sad scenario where an application is fully consuming CPU to limit it. To do so, you will need a magic command called Cpulimit that will help you to limit a PID to a desired percentage usage of your CPU.
I&amp;rsquo;ve wrote a little documentation on cpulimit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx Substitutions Filter : change of the fly page content</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/14/nginx-substitutions-filter-change-of-the-fly-page-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/14/nginx-substitutions-filter-change-of-the-fly-page-content/</guid>
      <description>Nginx Substitutions Filter is a filter module able to do both regular expression and fixed string substitutions on response bodies. This module is quite different from the Nginx&amp;rsquo;s native Substitution Module. It scans the output chains buffer and matches string line by line, just like Apache&amp;rsquo;s mod_substitute.
I&amp;rsquo;ve played with the classic substitution module but due to limitations (only one matching pattern and no regex), it wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy to do all I wanted to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deb_reboot : tells you if you need to reboot your Debian</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/12/deb_reboot-it-tells-you-if-you-need-to-reboot-your-debian-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 10:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/12/deb_reboot-it-tells-you-if-you-need-to-reboot-your-debian-or-not/</guid>
      <description>It´s been a while that I was waiting for a tool that tells me if my Debian server is requesting a reboot or not. Of course GUI tools exists (like Ubuntu update-manager), but on a server machine, where there is no X server installed (thankfuly), this kind of CLI tools can be quickly interesting.
That´s why I wrote a tool called deb_reboot that gives the reboot requierement information in parsing postinstall scripts of installed packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HAproxy : no more available on Wheezy :-(</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/10/haproxy-no-more-available-on-wheezy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/10/haproxy-no-more-available-on-wheezy/</guid>
      <description>How could this happen ? I found a communication on that and it has simply been removed as there were no updates since a long time. Even if CVE were recently proposed, it&amp;rsquo;s considered as not enough :
http://debian.2.n7.nabble.com/Status-of-haproxy-for-upcoming-wheezy-release-td2907665.html
But guys ! Seriously, do you know how many people are using HAproxy ? It&amp;rsquo;s a shame that it&amp;rsquo;s not in the current stable version of Debian. Now let&amp;rsquo;s check the availability on all Debian versions, it&amp;rsquo;s currently only on oldstable and experimental versions :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mincss : Easily minify you CSS</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/08/mincss-easily-minify-you-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 10:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/08/mincss-easily-minify-you-css/</guid>
      <description>I was searching a way to minify my CSS. For those who don’t know what it is, it’s a method to win space for your CSS as it will remove all unneeded blank spaces and lines return. A lot of websites exists to minify your CSS, but if your website is not online and only running locally, you won’t be able to minimize it.
I found a little software written in Python, that makes it easy, called mincss (thanks to Peter Bengtsson for it).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian Wheezy is finaly out :-)</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/06/debian-wheezy-is-finaly-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/05/06/debian-wheezy-is-finaly-out/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m so happy that Debian 7 is out :-) !
I&amp;rsquo;ve been running it since a few months on it (on my servers and as a desktop) and I congratulate Debian team for their work ! In the upcoming weeks I&amp;rsquo;ll try to start getting involved in some Debian&amp;rsquo;s packaging projects. My problem is : how many time do I have to give ?
One of my first taks, will be to integrate MySecureShell in the officials Debian repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NamedManager : une interface web agréable pour administrer Bind</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/26/namedmanager-une-interface-web-agreable-pour-administrer-bind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 10:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/26/namedmanager-une-interface-web-agreable-pour-administrer-bind/</guid>
      <description>Voici une interface web plutôt bien fichue qui permet de vous gérer vos serveurs Bind. Son nom est NamedManager. Elle sait aussi bien gérer des trucs classique, que des choses un peu plus poussée (la gestion automatique des PTR, le renseignement automatique un subnet, le multi serveurs&amp;hellip;) et en plus elle est élégante !
Je vous ai fait une doc pour sa mise en place qui n&amp;rsquo;est pas aussi simple qu&amp;rsquo;on pourrait l&amp;rsquo;imaginer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy-Queue : Un gestionnaire de queue pour cp et mv</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/22/copy-queue-un-gestionnaire-de-queue-pour-cp-et-mv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/22/copy-queue-un-gestionnaire-de-queue-pour-cp-et-mv/</guid>
      <description>Cela faisait un bail que j&amp;rsquo;attendais un soft de ce type, à tel point que je pensais en développer un au cas ou je ne trouve pas mon bonheur. Et par hasard, je suis tombé sur Copy-Queue qui fait exactement ce que je veux. A savoir, en ligne de commande, je peux faire des cp et des mv avec une gestion de file d&amp;rsquo;attente.
J&amp;rsquo;ai fais un petit article pour sa mise en place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LemonLDAP::NG du SSO sur mesure</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/20/lemonldapng-du-sso-sur-mesure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 10:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/20/lemonldapng-du-sso-sur-mesure/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai eu il y a quelques temps une petite formation par le mainteneur officiel de LemonLDAP::NG actuel (Clément Oudot). Superbe formation, surtout lorsqu&amp;rsquo;on voit ce que LdemonLDAP est capable d&amp;rsquo;apporter en terme de fonctionnalités par rapports à d&amp;rsquo;autres SSO. De plus son architecture et son mode de fonctionnement est très bien pensé.
Bref, un des hits aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui ! Seul petit b mol pour le moment, il n&amp;rsquo;est compatible qu&amp;rsquo;avec Apache. Si vous êtes un aficionados de Lighty ou Nginx, passez votre chemin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autossh sur un serveur de prod</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/16/autossh-sur-un-serveur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/16/autossh-sur-un-serveur/</guid>
      <description>Alors oui je sais, c&amp;rsquo;est vraiment pas propre en prod, mais que voulez vous&amp;hellip;on a pas toujours le choix, surtout quand on a pas la main sur l&amp;rsquo;infrastructure en question. J&amp;rsquo;ai eu besoin de mettre en place un tunnel SSH permanent (ce qui sous entends qu&amp;rsquo;il se reconnecte en cas de déconnexion), ça ne vous rappelle rien ? Un post que j&amp;rsquo;avais fait il y a quelques temps sur AutoSSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zsh powerlined</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/14/zsh-powerlined/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/14/zsh-powerlined/</guid>
      <description>Un peu à la manière de mon Tmux powerlined, j&amp;rsquo;ai fait un zsh powerline. Je suis en train de revoir du coup complètement ma configuration qui est devenu au fil du temps ingérable. Ma configuration n&amp;rsquo;est pas encore finie, mais est pleinement utilisable.
Si vous essayez et avez des suggestions, n&amp;rsquo;hésitez pas, je suis preneur :-). Vous pouvez récupérer ma configuration zsh sur mon git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tmux Powerlined</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/12/tmux-powerlined/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 10:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/12/tmux-powerlined/</guid>
      <description>Dans un précédent article, je vous parlait des fonts powerline et de l&amp;rsquo;adaptation de celles ci à tout pleins d&amp;rsquo;outils. J&amp;rsquo;ai pu récupérer d&amp;rsquo;un collègue sa configuration tmux powerline et l&amp;rsquo;ai adaptée à mes besoins. Le résultat ci dessus en screenshot, c&amp;rsquo;est booooooooo :-) !
Vous aurez donc besoin des fonts powerline et de ma configuration tmux que vous pouvez récupérer ici.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome powerlined</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/10/awesome-powerlined/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/10/awesome-powerlined/</guid>
      <description>Je vous l&amp;rsquo;avais récemment annoncé, je travaille maintenant avec l&amp;rsquo;environnement Awesome et l&amp;rsquo;ai tuné powerline. Je n&amp;rsquo;ai pas encore totalement fini ma configuration comme je le souhaite, mais c&amp;rsquo;est déjà pleinement utilisable pour le quotidien.
Vous pouvez récupérer ma configuration Awesome sur mon git. Dans le rc.lua, vous trouverez les packages à installer sur Debian Wheezy, ainsi que les instructions nécessaire à son installation. Une fois la configuration chargée, faites la touche Super (Windows) + F1 pour obtenir toute l&amp;rsquo;aide nécessaire au fonctionnement de ma configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fonts powerline</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/08/fonts-powerline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 10:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/08/fonts-powerline/</guid>
      <description>Depuis quelques temps, je refais quelques configuration vieillissantes pour les mettre au goût du jour. Entre autre, j&amp;rsquo;ai découvert par un collègue, les polices Powerline. Et j&amp;rsquo;ai kiffé. Comme le montre le screeshot ci dessus, ça nous fait des espèces de flèches jolies. Si je ne dis pas de bêtises, l&amp;rsquo;origine de ceci est un module pour Vim et aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui on commence à voir apparaître plusieurs outils utilisant ces powerlines. Je vous présenterais les miens dans les prochains jours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome : Mon nouvel environnement de bureau</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/06/awesome-mon-nouvel-environnement-de-bureau/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/06/awesome-mon-nouvel-environnement-de-bureau/</guid>
      <description>Ahhhhh, je crois que je vais enfin pouvoir me poser un moment ! J&amp;rsquo;ai enfin trouvé mon environnement de bureau pour être productif, ça s&amp;rsquo;appelle Awesome et comme son nom l&amp;rsquo;indique ça l&amp;rsquo;est ! Je tourne donc depuis 2 mois maintenant sous Awesome et suis ravis du résultat. C&amp;rsquo;est stable, très léger, embarque plusieurs mode de tilling est prévu pour le mouseless et dépourvu de toutes fioritures inutiles comme on peut trouver sous Ubuntu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcer un shell lors de logins LDAP</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/04/forcer-un-shell-lors-de-logins-ldap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/04/forcer-un-shell-lors-de-logins-ldap/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai récemment aidé un ancien collègue qui avait besoin d&amp;rsquo;une solution pour forcer des utilisateurs ayant déjà un shell LDAP à avoir un shell plus restreint de type lshell. La problématique est que si l&amp;rsquo;on change le shell au niveau LDAP, il faudra alors utiliser ce shell sur toutes les machines. Ce n&amp;rsquo;est donc tout simplement pas envisageable.
Par contre, il est possible de modifier les propriétés NSS lors du login :-).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian Wheezy : mise à jour du preseed</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/02/debian-wheezy-mise-a-jour-du-preseed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 10:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/04/02/debian-wheezy-mise-a-jour-du-preseed/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai en ce moment besoin d&amp;rsquo;installer beaucoup de machines, donc j&amp;rsquo;ai mis à jour le preseed que j&amp;rsquo;avais pour Squeeze et ai complété un peu plus ma documentation. Rien de bien sorcier, c&amp;rsquo;est juste ultra pratique de rien avoir à rentrer pour l&amp;rsquo;installation d&amp;rsquo;une machine et laisser la gestion du reste à Puppet par exemple.
Pour ceux qui veulent voir à quoi ça ressemble&amp;hellip;ça se passe ici.
J&amp;rsquo;en ai profité pour le mettre également sur mon git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrader la RAM de vos Mac, plus que possible</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/29/upgrader-la-ram-de-vos-mac-plus-que-possible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 11:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/29/upgrader-la-ram-de-vos-mac-plus-que-possible/</guid>
      <description>Il y a quelques années, j&amp;rsquo;avais déjà fait un upgrade de mon Mac Mini qui me sert aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui de serveur.
Maintenant, je commence a avoir de nouveaux besoins, nécessitant de plus en plus de ressources. J&amp;rsquo;avais déjà quelques problèmes d&amp;rsquo;I/O, ce qui m&amp;rsquo;a pousser à prendre un SSD et un besoin de plus des 4 Gb de mémoire installés. En parcourant la documentation de mon Mac mini, la taille maximale annoncée est de 4Gb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration vers ownCloud 5 réussie :-)</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/27/migration-vers-owncloud-5-reussie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 11:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/27/migration-vers-owncloud-5-reussie/</guid>
      <description>Et voilà encore une migration de faite. Elle s&amp;rsquo;est plutôt bien passée, alors que c&amp;rsquo;était mal partie. En effet, il a fallut que je change la configuration de mon Nginx pour que cette nouvelle mouture fonctionne. Ces informations n&amp;rsquo;étant pas marquées dans la documentation officielle, j&amp;rsquo;ai perdu un peu de temps en pensant que ma migration avait foirée.
En montant une autre plateforme from scratch, j&amp;rsquo;avais le même problème. Le soucis était alors rapidement identifiable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bugzilla : mise en place d’un outil de ticketing</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/23/bugzilla-mise-en-place-dun-outil-de-ticketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/23/bugzilla-mise-en-place-dun-outil-de-ticketing/</guid>
      <description>Il y a quelques temps, j&amp;rsquo;avais présenter OTRS. Dans le même esprit (mais plus orienté développement), on a l&amp;rsquo;ancien et vénérable Bugzilla qui fonctionne parfaitement et est utilisé encore aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui par de nombreuses sociétés ou pour des projets communautaires.
Je vous ai fait une petite documentation sur la mise en place de Bugzilla car j&amp;rsquo;ai du en installer une récemment. Si vous avez envie de jouer un peu avec, c&amp;rsquo;est l&amp;rsquo;occasion :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KVM : Suspendre ses guests à l’arrêt du host</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/21/kvm-suspendre-ses-guests-a-larret-du-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 11:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/21/kvm-suspendre-ses-guests-a-larret-du-host/</guid>
      <description>Pour faire suite à mon article précédent sur KVM en desktop, j&amp;rsquo;avais cherché comment suspendre les guests lorsque j’éteins ma machine, au lieu qu&amp;rsquo;ils soient arrêtés.
J&amp;rsquo;ai donc fais un petit article dessus :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remplacer VirtualBox par KVM sur son desktop</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/19/remplacer-virtualbox-par-kvm-sur-son-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 11:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/19/remplacer-virtualbox-par-kvm-sur-son-desktop/</guid>
      <description>KVM, quel merveilleux hyperviseur ! Je l&amp;rsquo;utilise depuis plusieurs années sur mes serveurs et je commence a l&amp;rsquo;utiliser sur ma workstation pour plusieurs raisons. Je vais comparer KVM a l&amp;rsquo;outil de virtualisation gratuit, a la mode : VirtualBox. Voici les raisons qui me poussent a passer a KVM :
 La licence : VirtualBox c&amp;rsquo;est bien, mais si je peux éviter toute dépendance avec Oracle, c&amp;rsquo;est mieux ! Je n&amp;rsquo;ai pas envie de connaître a fond une techno propriétaire qui peut d&amp;rsquo;un jour a l&amp;rsquo;autre basculer de gratuite à payante (faut pas oublier que c&amp;rsquo;est Oracle hein !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimisations SSD pour Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/03/optimisations-ssd-pour-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/03/03/optimisations-ssd-pour-linux/</guid>
      <description>Les SSD coûtent de moins en moins cher et leurs performances sont incroyables comparées a celles des disques classiques.
Pourtant, si on ne fait pas un peu de tuning pour les optimiser, on perd des performances (moins linéaires) avec le temps et on réduit surtout leurs durée de vie.
Récemment j&amp;rsquo;ai passé tous mes ordinateurs perso sous SSD et par chance au boulot j&amp;rsquo;ai pu être équipé d&amp;rsquo;une bête de course avec SSD également.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenElec : Solution multimedia pour Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/02/11/openelec-solution-multimedia-pour-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 11:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/02/11/openelec-solution-multimedia-pour-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>Pour faire suite à mon précédent article sur le Raspberry Pi, j&amp;rsquo;en ai fait une station multimedia en utilisant OpenElec.
OpenElec est une distribution GNU/Linux embarquée ayant pour but de permettre l’utilisation d’un centre multimédia (media center).
Voici un article pour mettre tout ceci en place, c&amp;rsquo;est très facile et fonctionne parfaitement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retour de Varnish, Nginx ne suffit pas !</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/02/07/retour-de-varnish-nginx-ne-suffit-pas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 11:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/02/07/retour-de-varnish-nginx-ne-suffit-pas/</guid>
      <description>Le titre de l&amp;rsquo;article en dit long. Depuis que je suis passé à Nginx, c&amp;rsquo;est vrai, c&amp;rsquo;est le jour et la nuit comparé à Apache. J&amp;rsquo;en suis extrêmement satisfait ! Cependant, malgré la gestion du cache via Nginx, les performances ne sont pas aussi bonnes qu&amp;rsquo;attendues.
J&amp;rsquo;ai donc testé Nginx avec Varnish, histoire de me refaire une opinion et effectivement Varnish fait vraiment la différence, non seulement côté temps de réponse, mais surtout côté CPU !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2ème et dernier jour au FOSDEM !</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/02/05/2eme-et-dernier-jour-au-fosdem-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 11:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/02/05/2eme-et-dernier-jour-au-fosdem-2/</guid>
      <description>Avant d&amp;rsquo;attaquer le 2 ème jour, je vais finir sur le premier (la suite d&amp;rsquo;hier).
Un des supers sujet était Bind 10 que j&amp;rsquo;attendais avec impatience. Il n&amp;rsquo;y a malheureusement eu d&amp;rsquo;informations sur les nouveautés aidant a la HA. Cependant il a été totalement réécrit pour supporter + de 100 cores alors qu&amp;rsquo;aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui au delà de 6, il y a des problèmes de performances. On a également (et étrangement) un serveur DHCP qui est intégré a Bind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Magazine sur Shinken</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/01/28/linux-magazine-sur-shinken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 11:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/01/28/linux-magazine-sur-shinken/</guid>
      <description>Je suis un fidèle lecteur de Linux Magazine et me suis récemment abonné à leurs journaux en PDF (enfin ! Marre des piles de Linux mag qui traînent chez moi).
Même si j&amp;rsquo;aime beaucoup ce que ces magazines proposent, tout ne m&amp;rsquo;intéresse pas et je dirais que c&amp;rsquo;est normal. Cependant ils font de temps en temps des hors série sur un sujet bien particulier qui permet de découvrir de nouveaux horizons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins : L’intégration continue</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/01/26/jenkins-lintegration-continue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2013 11:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/01/26/jenkins-lintegration-continue/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins est un outil open source d&amp;rsquo;intégration continue, fork de l&amp;rsquo;outil Hudson après les différends entre son auteur, Kohsuke Kawaguchi, et Oracle. Écrit en Java, Jenkins fonctionne dans un conteneur de servlets tel qu’Apache Tomcat, ou en mode autonome avec son propre serveur Web embarqué.
Dans le cadre de l&amp;rsquo;amélioration de Limesurvey comme cité dans un précédent ticket, le couplage Selenium/Jenkins est très pratique. J&amp;rsquo;ai donc fais une documentation sur la mise en place de Jenkins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium : Automatisation de tâches pour environnements web</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/01/24/selenium-automatisation-de-taches-pour-environnements-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 11:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/01/24/selenium-automatisation-de-taches-pour-environnements-web/</guid>
      <description>Dans le cadre d&amp;rsquo;amélioration des produits Open Source, je travaille avec un collègue en relation avec le créateur de LimeSurvey pour fournir une plateforme de test de non régression qui sera généreusement prêtée par Linagora.
Dans ce cadre, nous utilisons l&amp;rsquo;outil Selenium pour tester l&amp;rsquo;interface graphique car nous avons régulièrement observé des régressions sur ce produit. Selenium est donc très pratique et surtout d&amp;rsquo;une facilité déconcertante !
J&amp;rsquo;ai tout de même fait une documentation sur Selenium pour ceux que ça intéresse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP et Suhosin dans Debian c’est fini</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/01/10/php-suhosin-dans-debian-cest-finit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 11:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/01/10/php-suhosin-dans-debian-cest-finit/</guid>
      <description>C&amp;rsquo;est en migrant vers la dernière version de Debian (Wheezy) que je me suis rendu compte que php5-suhoshin avait disparu. Après quelques apt-cache et recherche sur le site de Debian, il n&amp;rsquo;y a effectivement plus de Suhoshin !
Pourquoi ? Tout simplement parce que les gars de chez Debian estiment que Suhoshin devrait être intégré mainstream dans le code de PHP et que ça ne devrait pas être aux distribution de les packager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ca y est, je suis passé à Nginx</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/01/06/ca-est-je-suis-passe-a-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 11:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2013/01/06/ca-est-je-suis-passe-a-nginx/</guid>
      <description>Fini le duo Apache/Varnish performant mais gourmand en ressources. Pour de gros sites, c&amp;rsquo;est certains que ce couple est très utile, mais pour mon blog, mon wiki et mes autre babioles, pas forcément !
Alors voilà, je suis passé à Nginx et après plusieurs jours dessus, je suis globalement satisfait. Petit bémol pour le stockage des éléments statiques qui n&amp;rsquo;est visiblement pas faisable sans passer par du proxy_pass. J&amp;rsquo;ai pu observer une gestion du cache globale moins efficace avec Nginx qu&amp;rsquo;avec Varnish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newznab : un indexeur de usenet</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/12/21/newznab-indexeur-de-usenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 11:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/12/21/newznab-indexeur-de-usenet/</guid>
      <description>Newznab est un indexeur de newznab. Il sert par exemple à être utilisé avec SABnzbd ou encore Sick-Beard. Il est ensuite très pratique de pouvoir faire des recherche par celui ci pour connaître par exemple les dernières distributions Linux sur les newsgroup ;-).
Pour sa mise en place, suivez le lien.
PS : si vous lisez cet article, c&amp;rsquo;est que c&amp;rsquo;était pas aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui la fin du monde :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppet : slides de présentation</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/12/15/2567/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/12/15/2567/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai récemment réalisé une présentation sur Puppet à mon taf pour mes collègues. A cet effet, j&amp;rsquo;ai créer des slides que j&amp;rsquo;ai partagé sur SlideShare. Si vous avez ce type de présentation en Français à faire, vous pouvez vous appuyer sur la mienne comme je l&amp;rsquo;ai fait sur d&amp;rsquo;autres :-)
La présentation est disponible en téléchargement sur slideshare ou Puppet Slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News en vrac</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/12/11/news-en-vrac-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 11:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/12/11/news-en-vrac-6/</guid>
      <description>Voici quelques petites modifications récemment effectuées sur le wiki :
 Kernel : J&amp;rsquo;ai mis à jour la documentation pour la recompilation des kernels. Pas de gros changements, juste un petit rafraîchissement graphique. Bind) : Petits correctifs sur quelques erreurs minimes Nagios : Une petite erreur sur l&amp;rsquo;installation, j&amp;rsquo;avais oublié &amp;lsquo;install&amp;rsquo; dans apt-get (Merci Sandro) Awk : Ajout d&amp;rsquo;un exemple awk Mediawki : J&amp;rsquo;ai mis à jour la page pour quelques petits trucs qui ont changés avec la dernière mouture de Mediawiki  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye bye /var/www</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/12/09/bye-bye-varwww/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 11:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/12/09/bye-bye-varwww/</guid>
      <description>C&amp;rsquo;est avec tristesse que je vous annonce la fin de /var/www. Ca faisait des années que je m&amp;rsquo;étais bien habitué à celà. C&amp;rsquo;est en installant Nginx sur Debian 7 que je me suis rendu compte que /var/www n&amp;rsquo;existait pas. J&amp;rsquo;ai donc regardé la conf et que vois je&amp;hellip;
root /usr/share/nginx/www;  J&amp;rsquo;ai donc regardé le README.Debian qui me renvoie sur l&amp;rsquo;explication : http://lintian.debian.org/tags/dir-or-file-in-var-www.html
Debian a tout simplement remis les choses propres en suivant la FHS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediawiki 1.20 et les URL courtes</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/12/07/2548/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/12/07/2548/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai récemment passé mon Mediawiki en 1.20. J&amp;rsquo;ai eu quelques petits soucis avec l&amp;rsquo;URL rewriting et les short URL. En effet, dans cette nouvelle version, ils ont supprimé le $wgUsePathInfo qui a du coup complètement cassé mes redirections.
J&amp;rsquo;ai finalement réussi à retrouver mon URL short mais d&amp;rsquo;une autre manière que je vous partage ici.
Bonne lecture</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 souris, 1 clavier et des ordinateurs</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/29/1-souris-1-clavier-des-ordinateurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 11:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/29/1-souris-1-clavier-des-ordinateurs/</guid>
      <description>Pour ceux qui n&amp;rsquo;ont pas encore la chance de connaître Synergy, je vais leur montrer un soft qui vaut le détour. Synergy, Kezako ?
Synergy vous permet de partager facilement votre souris et votre clavier entre plusieurs ordinateurs. Il est libre et Open Source. Il suffit de déplacer la souris d&amp;rsquo;un ordinateur à l&amp;rsquo;autre en passant par leurs bords, comme pour passer d&amp;rsquo;un écran à l&amp;rsquo;autre en multi-écran. Vous pouvez même partager les presse-papiers (copier-coller).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnome Shell : Ajouter une appli custom dans la liste des applis</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/25/gnome-shell-ajouter-une-appli-custom-dans-la-liste-des-applis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 11:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/25/gnome-shell-ajouter-une-appli-custom-dans-la-liste-des-applis/</guid>
      <description>On peut dire que même si je suis sous Xfce, Gnome Shell me manque et j&amp;rsquo;ai commencé à repasser certaines de mes machines dessus. Xfce est encore un peu jeune à mon goût (gestion du multi écran mal intégré, maximiser les fenêtres ne fonctionne pas tous le temps&amp;hellip;)
Et donc pour ajouter une Application dans la liste des Applications sous Gnome Shell, il faut se le faire à la main malheureusement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomcat : Mise en place du load balancer</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/23/tomcat-mise-en-place-du-load-balancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/23/tomcat-mise-en-place-du-load-balancer/</guid>
      <description>Toujours dans la continuité des articles sur Tomcat, on commence à rentrer dans du lourd et faire de la répartition de charge. Ça a l&amp;rsquo;avantage d&amp;rsquo;être assez facile et rapide à mettre en place. La mise en place du load balancing est faite au niveau du mod_jk comme ceci :
Je vous laisse regarder la doc pour sa mise en place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitorer son Tomcat</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/21/monitorer-son-tomcat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 11:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/21/monitorer-son-tomcat/</guid>
      <description>Ceci est le 2ème post sur Tomcat. Avoir un Tomcat en place c&amp;rsquo;est bien, le monitorer c&amp;rsquo;est mieux ! Il y a tellement de choses à faire attention sur Tomcat (du fait des contraintes de Java) qu&amp;rsquo;il est indispensable de le monitorer.
Il existe pour cela 2 manières :
 Via les URL Via la JMX (recommandé)  Je parle de ces 2 méthodes dans l&amp;rsquo;article sur Tomcat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache : installation du mod_jk</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/19/apache-installation-du-mod_jdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 11:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/19/apache-installation-du-mod_jdk/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai récemment joué avec Tomcat suite à une formation interne. C&amp;rsquo;est incroyable tout ce que cette application est capable de faire ! Je vous prépare donc une petite série d&amp;rsquo;articles sur Tomcat qui vous plairont je l&amp;rsquo;espère.
Le premier commence avec la mise en place de mod_jk sur Apache afin de servir du Tomcat par la suite. Pour sa mise en place, c&amp;rsquo;est ici.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenLDAP : La sauvegarde et restauration de schéma</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/13/openldap-la-sauvegarde-restauration-de-schema/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/13/openldap-la-sauvegarde-restauration-de-schema/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai un peu galérer à trouver des documentations claires sur la sauvegarde et restauration de schéma avec configuration d&amp;rsquo;un OpenLDAP v3.
Je vous fais partager ceci toujours sur mon Wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenLDAP : les ldif trop complets</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/09/openldap-les-ldif-trop-complets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 11:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/09/openldap-les-ldif-trop-complets/</guid>
      <description>Je viens d&amp;rsquo;apprendre qu&amp;rsquo;un export LDAP (LDIF) trop complet ne permet pas sa réimportation sous peine de se voir jeter l&amp;rsquo;erreur 19 à la gueule. En effet, il y a plusieurs champs qui ne doivent pas figurer dans un LDIF.
J&amp;rsquo;ai donc eu la chance de trouver des personnes a qui ce même problème est arrivé et j&amp;rsquo;ai donc fais un petit article pour parler de cette erreur sur laquelle j&amp;rsquo;ai passé 1h.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenLDAP : Les versions de fichiers de conf</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/03/openldap-les-versions-de-fichiers-de-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 11:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/03/openldap-les-versions-de-fichiers-de-conf/</guid>
      <description>Pour ceux qui avaient t&amp;rsquo;habitude de travailler sur d&amp;rsquo;anciennes configurations d&amp;rsquo;OpenLDAP (v1/v2), ou comme moi, ne font pas des installations tous les 4 matins, sachez que les fichiers de configurations ont changés et sont super casse pied à configurer maintenant à la main.
J&amp;rsquo;avais déjà observé ceci sur les Red Hat 6.3 et viens de le constater également sur une Debian 6. Donc pour configurer votre OpenLDAP v3, c&amp;rsquo;est devenu un tel casse tête qu&amp;rsquo;il y a des wizard pour l&amp;rsquo;aide à la mise en place&amp;hellip;et heureusement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTRS : Un bel outil de ticketing</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/01/otrs-bel-outil-de-ticketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 11:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/11/01/otrs-bel-outil-de-ticketing/</guid>
      <description>Cela fait fort longtemps que je connais ce soft, je n&amp;rsquo;en avais encore jamais mis en place. C&amp;rsquo;est ultra puissant (voir trop, tellement c&amp;rsquo;est complexe), alors je vous ai concocté une petite documentation pour sa mise en place avec un backend PostgreSQL.
Et hop, direction le wiki pour OTRS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentification SSO depuis Apache sur backend AD via Kerberos</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/10/26/authentification-sso-depuis-apache-sur-backend-ad-kerberos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 10:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/10/26/authentification-sso-depuis-apache-sur-backend-ad-kerberos/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai récemment aider un collègue sur la mise en place d&amp;rsquo;un SSO Apache sur un AD. J&amp;rsquo;ai trouvé ça techniquement joli, donc je vous ai fais une petite documentation que j&amp;rsquo;ai grossièrement pompée sur un autre site tellement je l&amp;rsquo;ai trouvé bien faites, et j&amp;rsquo;y ai fais quelques petites retouches. J&amp;rsquo;en ai profité pour mettre très légèrement à jour la documentation sur la mise en place d&amp;rsquo;un serveur Kerberos.
Pour la documentation sur l&amp;rsquo;Authentification SSO depuis Apache sur backend AD via Kerberos</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utiliser l’API de Sabnzbd</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/10/04/utiliser-lapi-de-sabnzbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 10:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/10/04/utiliser-lapi-de-sabnzbd/</guid>
      <description>Je trouve qu&amp;rsquo;il ne manque pas grand chose à Sabnzbd pour qu&amp;rsquo;il soit parfait. Cependant certaines options manquent et heureusement l&amp;rsquo;API est là pour compenser. J&amp;rsquo;ai donc écris un script en python permettant de jouer avec l&amp;rsquo;API que délivre Sabnzbd. Je l&amp;rsquo;ai créer dans l&amp;rsquo;idée qu&amp;rsquo;il soit facile de rajouter une fonctionnalité via l&amp;rsquo;API. Ce script permet :
 De voir les éléments que fournit l&amp;rsquo;API XML De supprimer un certain nombre d&amp;rsquo;éléments dans l&amp;rsquo;historique  J&amp;rsquo;espère que ça aidera certains à se plonger dedans, améliorer mon script ou bien utiliser les fonctions déjà existantes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La gestion de la mémoire sous Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/26/la-gestion-de-la-memoire-sous-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2012 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/26/la-gestion-de-la-memoire-sous-linux/</guid>
      <description>Ceci est mon dernier post sur le fonctionnement de la mémoire sous Linux. Je parle de :
 Swap Des fuites mémoires Des dirty et clean page L&amp;rsquo;OOM Kill  Ca se passe ici.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Les caches mémoire</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/24/les-caches-memoire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/24/les-caches-memoire/</guid>
      <description>Cette fois ci, je me suis attaqué aux caches Kernel. J&amp;rsquo;ai donc fais une petite doc pour comprendre comment ça fonctionne, pour voir leurs états et savoir comment les optimiser.
Cliquez ici pour lire cet article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L’adressage mémoire et son allocation</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/22/ladressage-memoire-son-allocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/22/ladressage-memoire-son-allocation/</guid>
      <description>Voici un nouveau post sur l&amp;rsquo;allocation de la mémoire. J&amp;rsquo;y aborde l&amp;rsquo;UMA, le NUMA, le tuning du TLB etc&amp;hellip;
Ça vous aidera certainement à comprendre comment la mémoire fonctionne si vous n&amp;rsquo;avez pas idée de comment les échanges et les caches sont gérés.
Ca se passe sur le wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimiser les performances de Sabnzbd</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/18/optimiser-les-performances-de-sabnzbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/18/optimiser-les-performances-de-sabnzbd/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai mis à jour l&amp;rsquo;article sur SABnzbd avec au menu du jour :
 Des optimisations de performances Utilisation des post scripts avec exemple  Comme toujours, j&amp;rsquo;espère que ça servira à d&amp;rsquo;autres et ça se passe sur le wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latence des process et kernel timing</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/16/latence-des-process-kernel-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/16/latence-des-process-kernel-timing/</guid>
      <description>Toujours dans mes articles d&amp;rsquo;optimisation, en voici un sur les latences et le cpu pinning. Je parle de :
 Taskset Cpuset IRQ balancing cpuspeed acpi  Voilà, il y a pas mal de choses à racconter là dessus alors si vous souhaitez en savoir plus, suivez le lien.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gestion des process et des schedulers sous Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/10/gestion-des-process-des-schedulers-sous-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/10/gestion-des-process-des-schedulers-sous-linux/</guid>
      <description>Toujours dans la continuité de l&amp;rsquo;amélioration des performances sous Linux, je parle cette fois ci des schedulers et la gestion des processus.
Ca se passe ici : Gestion des process et des schedulers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimisation des filesystems extX et du RAID sous Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/08/optimisation-des-filesystems-extx-du-raid-sous-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 10:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/09/08/optimisation-des-filesystems-extx-du-raid-sous-linux/</guid>
      <description>Pour continuer sur le précédent article d&amp;rsquo;optimisation des disques dur, en voici un autre sur le filesystem extX et le RAID logiciel sous Linux.
J&amp;rsquo;explique comment gagner en performance sur les filesystems et plonge un peu dans les méchanismes de la gestion des différents filesystems avec le kernel.
Pour lire l&amp;rsquo;article, suivez le lien.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimiser les performances des disques dur sur Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/08/31/optimiser-les-performances-des-disques-dur-sur-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/08/31/optimiser-les-performances-des-disques-dur-sur-linux/</guid>
      <description>Les disques dur physiques sont aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui ce qu&amp;rsquo;il y a de plus lent dans nos machines. Que ce soit les disques dur physique à plateaux ou bien même les SSD ! Mais il y a moyen d&amp;rsquo;optimiser selon les besoins des performances de ceux ci.
C&amp;rsquo;est pourquoi j&amp;rsquo;ai fais un article qui parle des bus, caches, elevators et options de queues. Pour le lire, c&amp;rsquo;est comme d&amp;rsquo;habitude sur le wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vérifier l’intégrité des fichiers sur sa Debian</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/08/29/verifier-lintegrite-des-fichiers-sur-sa-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 10:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/08/29/verifier-lintegrite-des-fichiers-sur-sa-debian/</guid>
      <description>Pour l&amp;rsquo;histoire, j&amp;rsquo;ai un ex collègue qui est tombé dans une boite magique avec tout pleins de servers owned depuis des années et pas de possibilités immédiates de les remplacer. Sachant que des binaires ont été modifiés, il a dû vérifier l&amp;rsquo;intégralité des systèmes. Pour cela il a fait un petit script, qui permet de vérifier tout ça.
Pour le script, c&amp;rsquo;est sur le wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoSSH : reconnecter automatiquement un tunnel SSH</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/08/15/autossh-reconnecter-automatiquement-tunnel-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 10:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/08/15/autossh-reconnecter-automatiquement-tunnel-ssh/</guid>
      <description>Si comme moi vous avez un tunnel à maintenir en permanence, qu&amp;rsquo;en cas de déconnexion vous souhaitez une reconnexion automatique, il vous faut utiliser alors un outil tel que AutoSSH.
Allez voici la doc pour mettre rapidement ça en place pour ceux que ça intéresse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mcollective : gérer une ferme de noeuds</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/08/13/mcollective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/08/13/mcollective/</guid>
      <description>Vous vous rappelez peut être de mon fameux Puppet Push qui me permettait d&amp;rsquo;exécuter des puppet client sur des hosts choisis.
Mcollective fait la même chose, mais en mieux et propose pleins de fonctionnalités en plus. Bref, il vous permet de contrôler tout un tas de machines très facilement et s&amp;rsquo;intègre très bien à Puppet. C&amp;rsquo;est d&amp;rsquo;ailleurs aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui ce que j&amp;rsquo;utilise en production. Plutôt qu&amp;rsquo;un long discourt, je vous laisse voir ma doc sur Mcollective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppet : installation du serveur (Master)</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/28/puppet-installation-du-serveur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 10:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/28/puppet-installation-du-serveur/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai mis à jour la documentation sur Puppet sur la partie installation et la configuration du serveur. Je prépare quelques autres mises à jour de cet article qui vous aideront j&amp;rsquo;espère, à mettre en place ce type de solution qui devient très très vite indispensable :-)
Voici la mise à jour de l&amp;rsquo;installation et la configuration du puppet master.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parted mon amour</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/16/parted-mon-amour/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 10:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/16/parted-mon-amour/</guid>
      <description>Oh oui parted c&amp;rsquo;est bien, ça gère l&amp;rsquo;alignement des disques, c&amp;rsquo;est scriptable, ça gère les volumes supérieur à 2Tb&amp;hellip;bref le kiffe !
Donc cooooooomme d&amp;rsquo;habitude, j&amp;rsquo;ai mis à jour le petit article sur Parted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mais arrêtez vos renommage d’interfaces réseaux !!!</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/14/mais-arretez-vos-renommage-dinterfaces-reseaux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/14/mais-arretez-vos-renommage-dinterfaces-reseaux/</guid>
      <description>Pourquoi tant de haine ? Sérieusement, je ne comprends toujours pas pourquoi Solaris et maintenant Red Hat nous poussent à ce que les interfaces réseaux possèdent le nom court du chipset des cartes. C&amp;rsquo;est tellement chiant lorsque l&amp;rsquo;on souhaite gérer un parc informatique de manière automatisée.
Bref, j&amp;rsquo;ai donc fais un petit article pour dire comment revenir à nos bonnes vieilles interfaces en ethX. C&amp;rsquo;est pas ici.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BTRFS…enfin !</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/12/btrfs-enfin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 10:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/12/btrfs-enfin/</guid>
      <description>Bon&amp;hellip;on est encore loin du compte par rapport au ZFS hein ! Mais par rapport à l&amp;rsquo;extX, c&amp;rsquo;est vraiment un pas de géant. Etant donné que la première version stable du BTRFS est sortie, je me suis dis qu&amp;rsquo;il était temps de faire un article là dessus.
Si vous avez envie de voir ce qu&amp;rsquo;est un filesystem avancé, je vous conseil fortement de commencer à vous y mettre car c&amp;rsquo;est l&amp;rsquo;avenir sous Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian 7 est freezée :-)</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/04/debian-7-est-freezee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 10:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/04/debian-7-est-freezee/</guid>
      <description>Debian 7 est freezée !!! J&amp;rsquo;espère qu&amp;rsquo;on aura la joie d&amp;rsquo;avoir cette nouvelle mouture pour la fin d&amp;rsquo;année :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Les preferences APT de Debian</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/02/les-preferences-apt-de-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/07/02/les-preferences-apt-de-debian/</guid>
      <description>Je viens de mettre à jour mon article sur les préférences Debian, car le miens était un peu vieillot. Bref, il y a un peu plus d&amp;rsquo;explications claires et surtout, un tableau que j&amp;rsquo;ai choppé sur le site de Debian qui est très utile.
Voici donc l&amp;rsquo;article mis à jour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nagios, CheckMk et Thruk sont dans un bateau</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/06/30/nagios-checkmk-et-thruk-sont-dans-un-bateau/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 10:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/06/30/nagios-checkmk-et-thruk-sont-dans-un-bateau/</guid>
      <description>Toi aussi tu rêves d&amp;rsquo;avoir une infrastructure Nagios éclatée ? Tu en as marre d&amp;rsquo;avoir des latences qui te foutent la merde sur tes alertes alors qu&amp;rsquo;il n&amp;rsquo;y a réellement aucun soucis ou simplement une micro coupure sur ta ligne de monitoring ? Et en plus de tout ça tu dois gérer de multiples filiales pour monitorer les mêmes choses ! Ne cherches pas plus loin petit padawan ! La documentation suivante est faite pour toi !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News en vrac</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/06/28/news-en-vrac-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/06/28/news-en-vrac-5/</guid>
      <description>Voici quelques petites modifications récemment effectuées sur le wiki :
 La doc sur puppet a été mise à jour avec une gestion des certificats un peu plus évoluée et divers utilisations plus poussées. Dans quelques temps il va y avoir une grosse mise à jour de cette documentation avec des optimisations, des fonctions, des facts&amp;hellip; tout pour vous aider à faire un beau puppet quoi :-) Ajout de &amp;ldquo;comment se sortir de la merde après une maj mediawiki&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Utilisation avancée de KVM</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/06/22/utilisation-avancee-de-kvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/06/22/utilisation-avancee-de-kvm/</guid>
      <description>Vous allez voir dans quelques temps que le blog, ainsi que le wiki vont tracer ! Avec mon pote Evoxmusic, on vient de se prendre une dedibox de la mort. Nous en profitons donc pour utiliser KVM et avons recours à des fonctionnalités un peu plus avancées que start and stop. Par exemple :
 Utilisation des VMs en NAT Une configuration iptables pour passer le NAT Ajouter des disques à chaud Dédier des CPU à une VM  J&amp;rsquo;ai donc mis à jour la documentation sur KVM avec les fonctionnalités citées ci dessus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postfix SASL</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/06/08/postfix-sasl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 10:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/06/08/postfix-sasl/</guid>
      <description>Toujours dans les mises à jour de documentation, j&amp;rsquo;ai mis à jour celle sur Postfix et le SASL, avec notamment une belle bourde sur la génération du certificat SSL (merci Rod).
Voici la doc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerDNS : Un beau serveur de cache</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/29/powerdns-un-beau-serveur-de-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 10:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/29/powerdns-un-beau-serveur-de-cache/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai récemment fait un article sur la mise en place d&amp;rsquo;un serveur PowerDNS maitre. En voici un sur le cache. C&amp;rsquo;est très rapide à mettre en place :-)
Voici la documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerAdmin : une interface web de gestion de PowerDNS</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/27/poweradmin-une-interface-web-de-gestion-de-powerdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2012 10:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/27/poweradmin-une-interface-web-de-gestion-de-powerdns/</guid>
      <description>PowerAdmin est une interface d&amp;rsquo;administration pour PowerDNS. Elle est faite en PHP et permet de gérer bien plus que la majorité des fonctionnalités de base de PowerDNS.
Elle est très utile si vous avez un backend MySQL qui n&amp;rsquo;est pas très pratique pour ajouter des enregistrements/zones ou toucher à la configuration de PowerDNS.
Pour la mise en place de cette interface, c&amp;rsquo;est par ici.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerDNS : un concurrent de Bind</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/25/powerdns-un-concurrent-de-bind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2012 10:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/25/powerdns-un-concurrent-de-bind/</guid>
      <description>PowerDNS est (comme son nom l&amp;rsquo;indique) un serveur DNS. C&amp;rsquo;est un concurrent direct à Bind. Il se veut moins gourmand en RAM et offre une utilisation de configuration plus souple que Bind.
PowerDNS est découpé en plusieurs rôles :
 Maitre Cache  J&amp;rsquo;ai donc fais une petite documentation sur la partie Maitre. Suivez le guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DJ Port Série, à l’ancienne…Tonight we are…</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/23/dj-port-serie-a-lancienne-tonight-we-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2012 10:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/23/dj-port-serie-a-lancienne-tonight-we-are/</guid>
      <description>Derrière ce titre pompeux se cache en fait la méthode pour activer le port série au démarrage d&amp;rsquo;une machine. Cette solution s&amp;rsquo;avère vite pratique lorsque l&amp;rsquo;on souhaites accéder à certaines machines qui ne répondent plus, ou bien via des solutions de virtualisation.
C&amp;rsquo;est pourquoi je vous ai concocté :
 Une petite doc sur le port série sous Linux Une petite doc sur le port série sous FreeBSD Une mise à jour de la doc de KVM pour pouvoir y accéder cash (oui comme tabata)  &amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FSCK à chaud sur EXT3/4</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/13/fsck-a-chaud-sur-ext34/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2012 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/13/fsck-a-chaud-sur-ext34/</guid>
      <description>Ouuuuuuuu le titre est kiffant hein ! Toi aussi tu as des contraintes super chaude de disponibilité, tu n’as pas la chance d’avoir du ZFS sur ton OS du bien ou tu te dis que BTRFS c’est encore trop jeune et tu dois supporter de l’ext encore quelques temps ?
Alors ceci est fait pour toi !!! J&amp;rsquo;ai concocté un petit script (un peu sale oui je l&amp;rsquo;avoue, mais il a le mérite de bien fonctionner) que j&amp;rsquo;ai pomper sur une discussion Red Hat permettant donc de jouer avec les snapshot pour fsckiser (oui le verbe) à la volée tous les LV de type ext3 et 4 sur une machine !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wake On Lan sur mac mini</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/11/wake-on-lan-sur-mac-mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/11/wake-on-lan-sur-mac-mini/</guid>
      <description>Le mac mini c’est quand même une belle bête. Et sous Debian, c’est la vie ! Donc pour cela, quoi de mieux que d’activer le wake on lan quant il y a besoin d’utiliser cette petite bêbette ?!
J&amp;rsquo;ai mis à jour ma documentation sur le mac mini avec le wake on lan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KayVillaiMme Paiourfourmanncizes</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/09/kayvillaimme-paiourfourmanncizes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/09/kayvillaimme-paiourfourmanncizes/</guid>
      <description>Je suis actuellement en train de refaire un de mes petits serveurs sous KVM et je me suis penché du côté des performances. Il y en a quelques unes indispensable si on veut avoir de bons résultats.
J&amp;rsquo;ai donc retaper ma documentation sur KVM avec des ajouts de perfs, config réseaux avec VLAN et 2&amp;frasl;3 autres babioles. Je vous laisse regarder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News en vrac</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/03/news-en-vrac-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/03/news-en-vrac-4/</guid>
      <description>Voici quelques petites modifications récemment effectuées sur le wiki :
Netcat : laisser le port d&amp;rsquo;écoute ouvert après une première connection
Bonding : Les options qu&amp;rsquo;il faut utiliser lorsque l&amp;rsquo;on a plusieurs bonding
Puppet : mise à jour de la documentation pour les versions les plus récentes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grub : kernel de secours</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/01/1797/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/05/01/1797/</guid>
      <description>Vous n&amp;rsquo;avez jamais rêver de booter sur un kernel qui fonctionne si un nouveau que vous venez d&amp;rsquo;installer crash ? Grub l&amp;rsquo;a fait :-)
Pour sa mise en place, c&amp;rsquo;est facile, quelques lignes par ci par là, rien à installer, c&amp;rsquo;est intégré depuis un moment d&amp;rsquo;ailleurs, mais on en entends pas souvent parler. Alors voilà une petite doc qui en parle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mme Irma peut surveiller tes serveurs</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/03/28/mme-irma-peut-surveiller-tes-serveurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 11:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/03/28/mme-irma-peut-surveiller-tes-serveurs/</guid>
      <description>ENNNFINNNN une belle interface pour Collectd !!! Merciiiiiiii !
Il y en a marre des interfaces pourries pour Collectd. Voici une belle interface qui fait bien plus que ça et ça s&amp;rsquo;appelle Observium.
Voici une petite documentation pour la mise en place avec Collectd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast and Reboot</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/03/22/fast-and-reboot-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 11:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/03/22/fast-and-reboot-18/</guid>
      <description>Reboot de ta machine en quelques secondes ça t’intéresse ? Kexec est fait pour toi mon ptit pot !
Tu colle des néons, une waste gate et 2 bombes de nitro et biiiiim tu reboot en quelques secondes ! Kexec va t&amp;rsquo;éviter de te taper touuuuuuuute la couche de reboot hardware qui prend toujours 10 piges sur les serveurs. Comment tu met ça en place dans ta caisse man ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lé boundingue</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/03/20/le-boundingue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/03/20/le-boundingue/</guid>
      <description>Toua vouloir en saortie dou té carte raizo oune daibi day batouarde y dé la toulayronce dé paoune ? Boua ya lou boundigue paour ça !
Tou trouvra la doc paour là.
Note : Cette doc existait déjà, mais je lui ai fait un changement de sexe une cure de jouvance et l&amp;rsquo;ai mise à jour pour Red Hat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udev : le choix de son device</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/03/12/udev-le-choix-de-son-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/03/12/udev-le-choix-de-son-device/</guid>
      <description>Vous avez toujours entendu que Linux c’était génial, qu’on pouvait faire tout ce que l’on voulait dessus, tout changer, tout mdifier…et là peut être qu’en réfléchissant un peu, vous vous dites : “C’est vrai ! On peut tout modifier…mais peut être pas ce qu’il y a dans /dev ?!”.
Et bien si et on peut en faire des choses dans ce /dev ! Je vous ai donc concocté une petite documentation sur ce merveilleux udev qui vous permettra de lancer des scripts au branchement d&amp;rsquo;un périphérique, de modifier le nom d&amp;rsquo;un device qui apparait dans /dev, de renomer /dev en /mes_periph_de_batard et moulte modifications de la muerta !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load balancer plusieurs connections WAN</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/03/03/load-balancer-plusieurs-connections-wan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2012 11:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/03/03/load-balancer-plusieurs-connections-wan/</guid>
      <description>J’ai récupérer la configuration d’un ex collègue qui avait fait une super documentation sur le sujet et qui permet de load balancer sur 2 interfaces wan.
Voici la documentation et merci Fabien.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxychains : laissez moi sortir !!!</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/02/28/proxychains-laissez-moi-sortir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 11:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/02/28/proxychains-laissez-moi-sortir/</guid>
      <description>Ahhhh les proxy au taf ou à l’école !!! C’est pénible ! Bref, il arrive parfois que l’on souhaites vraiment avoir accès temporairement à l’extérieur. Quelles que soient les commandes que vous utilisez vous aurez ou non la possibilité de configurer l’utilisation d’un proxy en modifiant un fichier de configuration, une variable de d’environnement etc…
L&amp;rsquo;intérêt de proxychains est que la configuration ne se fait qu&amp;rsquo;une seule fois, dans son propre fichier de configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tmux Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/02/24/tmux-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 11:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/02/24/tmux-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>Je ne me suis pas mis au LaTeX pour rien, j’avais pour idée de pondre une Cheat Sheet sur Tmux, vu que je n’en avais trouvé aucune sur le net.
J&amp;rsquo;ai donc mis à jour la documentation Tmux avec les Cheat Sheet en anglais et français.
Je les fournis également ici :
 Tmux French Cheat Sheet
 Tmux English Cheat Sheet
  N&amp;rsquo;hésitez pas à me faire un retour ou des propositions sur d&amp;rsquo;éventuels ajouts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vous prendrez bien une adresse IP ?!</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/01/26/vous-prendrez-bien-une-adresse-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 11:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/01/26/vous-prendrez-bien-une-adresse-ip/</guid>
      <description>J’ai mis à jour la documentation sur les serveurs DHCP. Pas de grosses modifs mais plutôt un ajout des confs Red Hat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Varnish : accélérez vos serveurs web</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/01/14/varnish-accelerez-vos-serveurs-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 11:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2012/01/14/varnish-accelerez-vos-serveurs-web/</guid>
      <description>Varnish est un serveur de cache très connu et utilisé pour accélérer les serveurs web. Je l&amp;rsquo;ai mis en place pour le blog et le wiki alors n&amp;rsquo;hésitez pas à me dire si vous trouvez que c&amp;rsquo;est plus rapide.
C&amp;rsquo;est rapide à mettre en place et j&amp;rsquo;ai fais une petite documentation comme à mon habitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FREEZE, don’t move !!!</title>
      <link>http://blog.deimos.fr/2010/08/06/freeze-dont-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 19:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.deimos.fr/2010/08/06/freeze-dont-move/</guid>
      <description>C’est un peu ce que diraient les poulet ricains pour ce qui est de la prochaine mouture de Debian. Car youpi tralala Debian 6 vient de freezer en version testing. Maintenant, il n’y aura donc que des corrections de bugs et de failles de secu.
Et ça tombe super bien ça ! Parce que je viens de réinstaller mon serveur (sur mon mac mini) et j&amp;rsquo;ai justement utiliser Debian 6 (je ferais un post bientôt là dessus).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>