<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Databases on Deimosfr Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/tags/databases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Databases on Deimosfr Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.deimos.fr/tags/databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Cassandra in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2018/06/24/running-cassandra-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2018/06/24/running-cassandra-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>For my own company MySocialApp, I&amp;rsquo;m managing multiple Cassandra clusters on top of a Kubernetes on premise cluster. For those who never heard of this distributed database, here is the summary from the official website:
 The Apache Cassandra database is the right choice when you need scalability and high availability without compromising performance. Linear scalability and proven fault-tolerance on commodity hardware or cloud infrastructure make it the perfect platform for mission-critical data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: Neo4j role available on Ansible Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2015/02/27/ansible-neo4j-role-available-on-ansible-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2015/02/27/ansible-neo4j-role-available-on-ansible-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>For a new project (will talk about it later), I needed to use Neo4J (graph database if you don&amp;rsquo;t know it yet).
I tried to cover more features than the current existing Ansible roles available on Ansible Galaxy. More will come in the next weeks. I also tried to make it simple to install it and do not force dependencies at maximum. Here are parameters you can set:
# Select neo4j version neo4j_package: neo4j # community version #neo4j_package: neo4j-advanced #neo4j_package: neo4j-enterprise  # Neo4j spatial plugin neo4j_install_spatial: false neo4j_spatial_version: &amp;#39;0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress: how I almost lost my blog and want to switch</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2015/01/29/wordpress-how-i-almost-lost-my-blog-and-want-to-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2015/01/29/wordpress-how-i-almost-lost-my-blog-and-want-to-switch/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I wanted to play with HAProxy SSL offloading. It was a good experience and alternative to Nginx SSL offloading (I already talked about in this blog). But this is not the topic here&amp;hellip;
When I was trying to make the offload working on the blog, I modified WordPress options which switched my blog into an infinite loop mode. As it was late and I was tired (bad idea), I just wanted to rollback my changes and needed to recover a SQL backup to do it fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: Fluentd and Kibana playbooks updated</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/12/09/ansible-fluentd-and-kibana-playbooks-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 11:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/12/09/ansible-fluentd-and-kibana-playbooks-updated/</guid>
      <description>Following the deployment blog post I made on ES/Kibana/Fluentd, I released new version of Fluentd and Kibana playbooks to support the latests versions of themselves and ElasticSearch.
ElasticSearch 1.4 version is ,out which doesn&amp;rsquo;t changed anything for the deployment. However Kibana requires to enable an ElasticSearch configuration option now, to work properly. I updated the Kibana playbook for it.
On its side, Fluentd has the major release 2.0 out and I updated Ansible playbook for the best integration with Debian Wheezy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News in bulk</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/11/07/news-in-bulk-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 11:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/11/07/news-in-bulk-4/</guid>
      <description>As I do not really have a good blog post for today, here are some things I wanted to talk in a summary. Some good projects have been updated like:
 WordPress 4: no big updates at the first view but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to see how this project works and grow (videos, WYSIWYG,&amp;hellip;) HAProxy 1.5: Offlloading SSL embedded, Full HTTP Keepalive, ACL enhancement&amp;hellip; BIG update! MySecureShell 2.0: Using GnuTLS instead of OpenSSL, available in Debian upstream repositories, new doc&amp;hellip; Nginx 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galera Innoptimizer: now support tables’ partition</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/08/galera-innoptimizer-now-support-tables-partition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 10:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/10/08/galera-innoptimizer-now-support-tables-partition/</guid>
      <description>You may remember the first introduction of that tool here. I&amp;rsquo;ve made changes to support tables&amp;rsquo; partition, to avoid a big lock on huge tables.
The solution is to rebuild every partition one by one instead of rebuilding the whole table. This is smoother and less stressing Galera. I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy this new version (v0.2).
Note: I still got issues on MariaDB 10 with such thing, I&amp;rsquo;m working on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadoop meetup on monday in Paris</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/20/hadoop-meetup-on-monday-in-paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/20/hadoop-meetup-on-monday-in-paris/</guid>
      <description>Next Monday will take place a Hadoop meetup. I already heard of it but didn&amp;rsquo;t tested it yet. This meetup can help you more on what it is and technique usages.
If you want to know more about this meetup, please follow the link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ElasticSearch setup HA and basic usages</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/10/elasticsearch-setup-ha-and-basic-usages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/10/elasticsearch-setup-ha-and-basic-usages/</guid>
      <description>I recently played with ElasticSearch Cluster and I totally fall in love! How easy it is, everything is automatic, it works perfectly, wowwww!!!
I made a little documentation on how to setup one, you can find it there.
ElasticSearch is a really powerful solution and I really like working with it. If you&amp;rsquo;re searching a full text search solution, try ElasticSearch, you&amp;rsquo;ll be happy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neo4j: a pretty graph database</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/06/neo4j-a-pretty-graph-database-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 10:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/06/neo4j-a-pretty-graph-database-2/</guid>
      <description>I forgot to talk about 1 meetup I&amp;rsquo;ve been regarding Neo4j. A friend (evomusic) talked to me about it and as I&amp;rsquo;m curious, I went to this meetup in July. Neo4j is a highly scalable, robust (fully ACID) native graph database. Neo4j is used in mission-critical apps by thousands of leading startups, enterprises, and governments around the world.
I you don&amp;rsquo;t know what is a graph database, it&amp;rsquo;s a very good introduction and will help you to understand what it is and how it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediawiki: make your search case insensitive</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/31/mediawiki-make-your-search-insensitive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/31/mediawiki-make-your-search-insensitive/</guid>
      <description>For several years, I was wondering how to make Mediawiki search case insensitive. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really had time to look at it until I was really fed up. That&amp;rsquo;s why after a few seconds of search, I&amp;rsquo;ve found an extension for Mediawiki which is working perfectly called TitleKey.
 The TitleKey extension provides a case-insensitive title prefix search. It uses a separate table for the keys, so if it works cleanly it can be deployed without an expensive rebuild of core tables, and dumped when Wikimedia gets a nicer backend through Extension:LuceneSearch (pre 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Book: MariaDB High Performance available for pre-order</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/23/my-book-mariadb-high-performance-available-for-pre-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/23/my-book-mariadb-high-performance-available-for-pre-order/</guid>
      <description>All, I&amp;rsquo;m proud to announce my first book available for pre-order! I&amp;rsquo;m really happy to have finished it and see after several months of hard work that it will be soon available.
Who is this book for?
 MariaDB High Performance is aimed at system administrators/architects or DBAs who want to learn more about how to grow their current infrastructure to support larger traffic.
Before beginning with this book, we expect you to be well–practised with MySQL/MariaDB for common usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ElasticSearch Book to read</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/17/elasticsearch-book-to-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 10:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/17/elasticsearch-book-to-read/</guid>
      <description>I really like working on ElasticSearch, so powerful, so easy to use, so scalable and so high available. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a very interresting book I bought on it.
It will help you to start with ElasticSearch and answer a lot of question you may have regarding the product. If you want to buy it, take a look there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy a logs management infrastructure (Elasticsearch&#43;Kibana&#43;Fluentd) with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/15/deploy-a-logs-managememt-infrastructure-elasticsearchkibanfluentd-with-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/15/deploy-a-logs-managememt-infrastructure-elasticsearchkibanfluentd-with-ansible/</guid>
      <description>During the last weeks I started to play with Elasticsearch, Fluentd and Kibana. I made a documentation to help on deploying it easily.
As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;m an Ansible fan, so I made Ansible playbooks to deploy a complete infrastructure (server and clients). They will deploy this kind of architecture:
On the client side, Fluentd clients will get syslog and Nginx logs, to send them to the Fluentd server. On the server side, a Fluentd receiver will be there to get data from other Fluentd clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog posts slowdown for some weeks</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/22/blog-posts-slowdown-for-some-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/22/blog-posts-slowdown-for-some-weeks/</guid>
      <description>Hello readers!
The numbers of readers keeps growing and I really appreciate it :-). Thanks to all followers!
You may know that I&amp;rsquo;m currently writing a book on MariaDB performances/high availability. I&amp;rsquo;m almost finish and this is the last run before the publication in September.
To give the maximum in this book , in the very short delay I have to, I need more time. The current blog post flow is: one blog post every 2 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker 1.0 &amp; RedHat 7</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/18/too-many-new-software-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/18/too-many-new-software-versions/</guid>
      <description>I really like this kind of news, new versions of docker and RedHat:
 Docker 1.0: this is the first stable version after more than one year of development. This version is production ready and I will start using it asap. RedHat 7: this is a good news as the version 6 started to be a little bit old now. What&amp;rsquo;s new?  MariaDB replace MySQL \o/ Docker integrated systemd XFS by default Kernel 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ElasticSearch: meetup 7 in Paris next Tuesday</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/08/elasticsearch-meetup-7-un-paris-next-thuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/08/elasticsearch-meetup-7-un-paris-next-thuesday/</guid>
      <description>Next Tuesday, ElasticSearch will takes place. Last meetup was very interesting and technical.
I hope this one will be as good as the last one. There will be a talk from Dailymotion and an ElasticSearch Core developer.
To get more informations it&amp;rsquo;s here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup: discover MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/31/meetup-discover-mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/31/meetup-discover-mongodb/</guid>
      <description>A new french meetup MongoDB related will take place next Tuesday in Paris.
This will be a practical session to learn how to integrates and manage a MongoDB through Java. From shell and MongoDB drivers to make a website integration.
Thanks for the organization Duchess! To get more informations it&amp;rsquo;s here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logstash vs Fluentd</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/13/logstash-vs-fluentd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 10:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/13/logstash-vs-fluentd/</guid>
      <description>Regarding one of my latest post, talking about Fluentd, some of you asked me why I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen Fluentd instead of Logstash. First of all, I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at this blog post, which kindly resume the current situation. Looking at this and with feedback I got, I could establish this array:
   Logstash  Fluentd   Concerns  Flexibility/Interoperability  Simplicity/Robustness   Language  JRuby  Cruby   Inputs  More  Fewer   Inputs specs  Basics  Scalables   Plugins  Lot  Lot more   Plugins install  Simple (drop a jar)  Can be complex (dependencies)   Logs send crypt  Yes  Yes   Scalability  Forward to 2 hosts  LB A/A or A/P   Reliability  Can loss messages  No message loss    Logstash and Fluentd are both powerful solutions, they both got pros and cons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elasticsearch meetup next Wednesday in Paris</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/11/elasticsearch-meetup-next-wednesday-in-paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 10:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/11/elasticsearch-meetup-next-wednesday-in-paris/</guid>
      <description>Next Wednesday, a meetup will take place in Paris talking about Elasticsearch. My previous post was talking about a log solution using Elasticsearch.
During that meetup, an overview of how Elasticsearch powerful real-time capabilities enrich Hadoop development. The session will showcase how to perform real-time searches on top and within Hadoop, Hive, Pig or Cascading jobs to get better answers, fast.
We&amp;rsquo;ll cover architectural topics such as index scalability, data locality and partitioning between the Hadoop cluster and the search index, using off and on-premise storages (HDFS, S3, local file-systems) and multi-tenancy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickly search in your logs with Elasticsearch, Kibana and Fluentd</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/09/quickly-search-in-your-logs-with-elasticsearch-kibana-and-fluentd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/09/quickly-search-in-your-logs-with-elasticsearch-kibana-and-fluentd/</guid>
      <description>Managing logs is not a complicated tasks with classical syslog systems (syslog-ng, rsyslog&amp;hellip;). However, being able to search in them quickly when you have several gigabit of logs, with scalability, with a nice graphical interface etc&amp;hellip;is not the same thing.
Hopefully today, tools that permit to do it very well exists, here are the list of tools that&amp;rsquo;s we&amp;rsquo;re going to use to achieve it:
 Elasticsearch: Elasticsearch is a flexible and powerful open source, distributed, real-time search and analytics engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mysqlnd: replace your old php mysql client library by mysqlnd</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/05/mysqlnd-replace-your-php-mysql-library-libmysqlclient/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/05/mysqlnd-replace-your-php-mysql-library-libmysqlclient/</guid>
      <description>As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;m using and loving MariaDB. A colleague recently introduced me the benefits of the php built-in MySQL/MariaDB library (shame on me, I never heard of it). Here are the informations you can find from it on the MySQL website:
 The mysqlnd library is highly optimized for and tightly integrated into PHP. The MySQL Client Library cannot offer the same optimizations because it is a general-purpose client library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data meetup with Twitter feedbacks</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/03/big-data-meetup-with-twitter-feedbacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/05/03/big-data-meetup-with-twitter-feedbacks/</guid>
      <description>On next Monday, a meetup will take place in Paris concerning Big Data with Twitter feeback. This meetup will be live retransmitted through YouTube.
The main talk will speak about how Twitter did to scale to millions of users:
 Twitter is one of the most heavily trafficked sites on the internet, with over 240 million active users and serving over 500 million Tweets per day. Twitter, as a company and as a service has seen remarkable growth in its eight years of existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRM: automatic MySQL/MariaDB replication managment</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/25/prm-automatic-mysqlmariadb-replication-managment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/04/25/prm-automatic-mysqlmariadb-replication-managment/</guid>
      <description>The Percona replication manager (PRM) is a framework using the Linux HA resource agent Pacemaker that manages replication and provides automatic failover. This covers the installation of the framework on a set of servers. The PRM framework is made of 4 components: Corosync, Pacemaker, the mysql resource agent and MySQL itself.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to setup, better if you already know how to use Pacemaker and it works like a charm. In fact it setup a master and x slaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PuPHPet : speed up your Vagrant deployment</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/06/puphpet-speed-up-your-vagrant-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2013/08/06/puphpet-speed-up-your-vagrant-deployment/</guid>
      <description>Vagrant is a fast solution build on top of VirtualBox. I already talked about it in a previous post.
The thing is, you could do really more with Vagrant by adding Puppet manifests or Chef recipes in your Vagrant configuration file. For those who don&amp;rsquo;t often use one of those 2 softwares, it quickly could transform into a nightmare when they want to deploy softwares in addition of the OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MariaDB/MySQL slides for HA and performances tuning</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/21/mariadbmysql-slides-for-ha-and-performances-tuning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2013/06/21/mariadbmysql-slides-for-ha-and-performances-tuning/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave a training on MariaDB/MySQL regarding performances tuning and High Availability. You can find here the slides I&amp;rsquo;ve made for it (french).
Some subjects related in that document are replication master -&amp;gt; slave, master &amp;lt; -&amp;gt; master and Galera Cluster. You can download the PDF here or see it directly on SlideShare :
I hope this will help some of you to get a better understanding on some advanced features.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>