<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nousmotards on Deimosfr Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/categories/nousmotards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nousmotards on Deimosfr Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 13:00:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.deimos.fr/categories/nousmotards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero downtime upgrade with Ansible and HAProxy</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/21/zero-downtime-upgrade-with-ansible-and-haproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/21/zero-downtime-upgrade-with-ansible-and-haproxy/</guid>
      <description>Some of you may not be familiar with the terms &amp;ldquo;Rolling upgrade&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Rolling restart&amp;rdquo;. This is the action of upgrading or restarting a cluster without service interruption (alias zero downtime). In most cases, this is done node by node, but in fact it depends of the technology you&amp;rsquo;re managing and the number of active nodes in your cluster.
At Nousmotards we have several Java Spring Boot applications running. Restarting one application can take up to 1 min.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elasticsearch: How we speed up news feeds and user walls display</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/20/how-we-speed-up-news-feed-and-user-wall-display-using-elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/20/how-we-speed-up-news-feed-and-user-wall-display-using-elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
In my previous post, I talked about how to speed up reads and writes coupling Redis with Neo4J. Now I want to share with you how it&amp;rsquo;s possible to unload your server and use Elasticsearch to speed up news feed and user wall.
1/ Show me your news feed A news feed is the main page of traditional social networks. Its main goal is to show you all recents updates from your friends and your interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we use Neo4J on our social network and workaround performance issues</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/15/how-we-use-neo4j-on-our-social-network-and-workaround-performance-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 10:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/15/how-we-use-neo4j-on-our-social-network-and-workaround-performance-issues/</guid>
      <description>Neo4J is the most popular graph database in the NoSQL databases family. We&amp;rsquo;re using it in the Nousmotards project to store all social data through nodes and relationships.
Today I am going to talk about our experience after having using it for 2 years now (take a look at directed graph if you are not really familiar with Graph Database).
1/ Our use case Nousmotards is a social network for bikers, we aim to provide valuable tools to ride, meet and share nice time with people who like motorcycling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker: why you should use Monit instead of supervisord</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/13/docker-why-you-should-use-monit-instead-of-supervisord/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/13/docker-why-you-should-use-monit-instead-of-supervisord/</guid>
      <description>This title can sounds like a troll, but this is not the case! I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post as a feedback. When I spoke during an Ansible meetup presenting Nousmotards infrastructure, I had several questions regarding why I chose monit as the init system instead of supervisord. That&amp;rsquo;s what encouraged me to write this post and that&amp;rsquo;s why I wanted to clarify here the things.
Introduction Docker is made to run a process in a confined area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphite events on Debian jessie</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/08/graphite-events-on-debian-jessie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 11:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/08/graphite-events-on-debian-jessie/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m using Graphite at work and for my Nousmotards project. For Nousmotards, I&amp;rsquo;m using the Graphite version available in the default Debian Jessie repositories. This to avoid mismatch django dependencies etc&amp;hellip;
A few days ago, I wanted to try Graphite events to get something pretty cool in Grafana :
This to be able to know when a new app version is deployed and make it easier to understand when an issue occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible color and buffer fix on Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/07/ansible-color-and-buffer-fix-on-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 15:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2016/01/07/ansible-color-and-buffer-fix-on-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>Hi all ! Long time since last blog post ! I&amp;rsquo;m using Jenkins with Ansible on my Nousmotards project for building docker containers or deploying into production.
You may noticed that you&amp;rsquo;ve no Ansible color when running it into Jenkins! The simple way to correct it is to export an environment variable in your Jenkins job:
export ANSIBLE_FORCE_COLOR=true Now that&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool! However, you may also noticed that there&amp;rsquo;s some kind of lags on the console when you want to see a real time console log on Jenkins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Meetup done! Watch again the slides</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2015/09/15/ansible-meetup-done-watch-again-the-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 21:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2015/09/15/ansible-meetup-done-watch-again-the-slides/</guid>
      <description>The Ansible meetup ended ! That was really nice for my first one.
I had really great feedbacks and liked the questions when ended. More than that I met nice people after the meetup and could have interresting discussions :-). I&amp;rsquo;m really happy about it.
For those who would like to review the slides, you can find them here:
http://nousmotards.github.io/ansible-meetup-0915/
If you want to watch the video:
http://www.infoq.com/fr/presentations/reseau-social-motard
or view the PDF version here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Meetup with Nousmotards in Paris!!!</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2015/09/11/ansible-meetup-with-nousmotards-in-paris/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 20:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2015/09/11/ansible-meetup-with-nousmotards-in-paris/</guid>
      <description>A long long time since my last blog post ! I didn&amp;rsquo;t had the time to make one because of the time I spent on building Nousmotards infrastructure.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in how I built the infrastructure, come and see us on the Ansible Meetup next Tuesday 😉 The slides and video of the Meetup will be made and available on InfoQ.
If you&amp;rsquo;re a French biker, do not hesitate anymore!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>