<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lxc on Deimosfr Blog</title>
    <link>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/categories/lxc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lxc on Deimosfr Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 21:56:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/categories/lxc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Meetup done! Watch again the slides</title>
      <link>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2015/09/15/ansible-meetup-done-watch-again-the-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 21:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2015/09/15/ansible-meetup-done-watch-again-the-slides/</guid>
      <description>The Ansible meetup ended ! That was really nice for my first one.
I had really great feedbacks and liked the questions when ended. More than that I met nice people after the meetup and could have interresting discussions :-). I&amp;rsquo;m really happy about it.
For those who would like to review the slides, you can find them here:
http://nousmotards.github.io/ansible-meetup-0915/
If you want to watch the video:
http://www.infoq.com/fr/presentations/reseau-social-motard
or view the PDF version here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naemon/Nagios: LXC check resources</title>
      <link>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/09/02/naemonnagios-lxc-check-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/09/02/naemonnagios-lxc-check-resources/</guid>
      <description>You may know that I really like LXC and the major problem when you want to use that solution in production is: how do you monitor memory and CPU?
Regarding the CPU side, I do not have an easy answer for the moment :-(. However regarding the memory, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a Nagios/Naemon check which will check the memory (RAM) and SWAP of a container. Here is how to use it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC 1.0 on Debian Wheezy</title>
      <link>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/08/29/lxc-1-0-on-debian-wheezy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/08/29/lxc-1-0-on-debian-wheezy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m using for my own servers LXC for about a year now. I&amp;rsquo;m still fed up about bugs introduced by the beta version of LXC (0.8b) present in Debian Wheezy. As now LXC project has released a stable version, I&amp;rsquo;ve looked at the Debian backports, but didn&amp;rsquo;t have any chance to find a newer version on it :-(. However, a version 1.0.4 exist on Debian Jessie. I took the Debian sources and recompiled them on Wheezy (available here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC: ressources statistics</title>
      <link>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/06/16/lxc-ressources-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/06/16/lxc-ressources-statistics/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to find a way to properly view resources (memory/CPU/IO) usages or configuration. For that I need to use cgroups. But the problem are on free, top, htop or common any tools, as they do not get the real informations of the container.
We&amp;rsquo;re in fact waiting on a lot of work on the kernel side or systemd side. More information&amp;rsquo;s can be found here. Another solution that permit to bind a socks inside containers exists called CGManager, however classical tools doesn&amp;rsquo;t use it to get informations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from KVM to LXC…feedbacks</title>
      <link>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/06/10/migrating-from-kvm-to-lxc-feedbacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/06/10/migrating-from-kvm-to-lxc-feedbacks/</guid>
      <description>I recently migrated this server to a new one. New hardware, better performance, less power consumption etc&amp;hellip;Thanks Online.
I&amp;rsquo;m already using LXC on my home server and see the benefits for 8 months ago. That&amp;rsquo;s why I decided to migrate this server to LXC as well. The difference here is that I wanted to migrate my VM from KVM. All my KVM VM are on Debian Wheezy so that was pretty easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible: LXC role v1.1</title>
      <link>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/06/02/ansible-lxc-role-v1-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/06/02/ansible-lxc-role-v1-1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated my LXC role for ansible. You can get it like that:
ansible-galaxy install deimosfr.lxc  Here is the change log:
+ Adding new parameters for dnsmasq and interfaces + Adding new prequesite to avoid unwanted modules to load in the latest kernel versions = Corrected networking configuration issue = Templates do not create @LOCALSTATEDIR@ folder anymore  It works perfectly on my new Dedibox :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker: only 10 min to play with basics</title>
      <link>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/05/27/docker-10-min-to-play-with-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2014/05/27/docker-10-min-to-play-with-basics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of Docker a year ago, started to play with it for some months and really start using it a few days ago. At first, I thought it was more complex than expected and finally I saw how simple it is and how many time I&amp;rsquo;ve lost because I didn&amp;rsquo;t used it.
Docker is an open-source engine that automates the deployment of any application as a lightweight, portable, self-sufficient container that will run virtually anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC : my documentation finally finished</title>
      <link>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2013/11/30/lxc-my-documentation-finally-finished/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2013/11/30/lxc-my-documentation-finally-finished/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally finished my documentation on LXC for Debian Wheezy. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve added the most interesting features.
I&amp;rsquo;m now going to migrate my servers from KVM to LXC as I only POC it for now. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you up to date when everything will be migrated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC : how to convert a host/vm to a container</title>
      <link>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2013/09/11/lxc-how-to-convert-a-hostvm-to-a-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2013/09/11/lxc-how-to-convert-a-hostvm-to-a-container/</guid>
      <description>As you can see, I write more and more posts on LXC. The latest thing I worked on, was how to convert a host/vm to a LXC container. I needed to write a script for it as I didn&amp;rsquo;t find what I needed.
The script will remove unneeded elements in a Debian system, removing folders (dev,proc,sys), recreate devices and configure etc files. You can find more informations by following the link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC : Some little setbacks</title>
      <link>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2013/08/28/some-little-setbacks-with-lxc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://deimosfr.github.io/blog/2013/08/28/some-little-setbacks-with-lxc/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;m new to LXC, I am discovering how it works, see the maturity of the project and it&amp;rsquo;s integration in Debian. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a post a few weeks ago to introduce the basics and now I&amp;rsquo;m digging in advanced features.
I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered several issues. Most of them are not critical but unfortunately looks like a lack of integration on Debian.
 The first one is related to wheezy template and I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about it in a previous post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>