<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mariadb on Deimosfr Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/tags/mariadb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mariadb on Deimosfr Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 10:00:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.deimos.fr/tags/mariadb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Galera Innoptimizer: optimize tables without stress</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/30/galera-innoptimizer-optimize-tables-without-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/30/galera-innoptimizer-optimize-tables-without-stress/</guid>
      <description>I recently been faced on a classical problem on InnoDB which is the fragmentation, but on Galera. InnoDB engine doesn&amp;rsquo;t defragment on the fly and requires optimize maintenance sometimes to free disk space. But on Galera, which is a fault tolerance and high availability solution, it&amp;rsquo;s a problem having tables locked by an optimize procedure. Until Galera doesn&amp;rsquo;t support TokuDB and only fully support InnoDB, we had (with a colleague (Kevin aka Vinek)) to find a solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MariaDB book on High Performances is finally out! :-)</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/24/my-mariadb-book-on-high-performances-is-finally-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/09/24/my-mariadb-book-on-high-performances-is-finally-out/</guid>
      <description>The day has finally come! After several months of intensive work (weekends and nights), I&amp;rsquo;m proud to announce that my book on MariaDB High Performance is out!
In that book, I made my best to make things as simple as possible to test features, test solutions and to explain everything in the simplest way. Of course if you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner on MariaDB (and Linux), it may be hard. But if you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with basics and want to go further with performances and high availability on MariaDB, you&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>