<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Deimosfr Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Deimosfr Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 10:00:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.deimos.fr/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Book: MariaDB High Performance available for pre-order</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/23/my-book-mariadb-high-performance-available-for-pre-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/23/my-book-mariadb-high-performance-available-for-pre-order/</guid>
      <description>All, I&amp;rsquo;m proud to announce my first book available for pre-order! I&amp;rsquo;m really happy to have finished it and see after several months of hard work that it will be soon available.
Who is this book for?
 MariaDB High Performance is aimed at system administrators/architects or DBAs who want to learn more about how to grow their current infrastructure to support larger traffic.
Before beginning with this book, we expect you to be well–practised with MySQL/MariaDB for common usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ElasticSearch Book to read</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/17/elasticsearch-book-to-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 10:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/08/17/elasticsearch-book-to-read/</guid>
      <description>I really like working on ElasticSearch, so powerful, so easy to use, so scalable and so high available. I&amp;rsquo;ve found a very interresting book I bought on it.
It will help you to start with ElasticSearch and answer a lot of question you may have regarding the product. If you want to buy it, take a look there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book finished! Blog posts will continue</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/07/26/book-finished-blog-posts-will-continue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 10:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/07/26/book-finished-blog-posts-will-continue/</guid>
      <description>After 1 month to finish writing my book, it&amp;rsquo;s now done! I will continue to maintain the blog :-)
A lot of things happened during the last month. I started writing draft blog posts and I need to finish them.
Have a good weekend
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog posts slowdown for some weeks</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/22/blog-posts-slowdown-for-some-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/06/22/blog-posts-slowdown-for-some-weeks/</guid>
      <description>Hello readers!
The numbers of readers keeps growing and I really appreciate it :-). Thanks to all followers!
You may know that I&amp;rsquo;m currently writing a book on MariaDB performances/high availability. I&amp;rsquo;m almost finish and this is the last run before the publication in September.
To give the maximum in this book , in the very short delay I have to, I need more time. The current blog post flow is: one blog post every 2 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: The Hacker’s Guide to Python</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/26/book-the-hackers-guide-to-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 11:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/03/26/book-the-hackers-guide-to-python/</guid>
      <description>One of my colleague (Julien Danjou) wrote a book on advanced usage of Python. The book was out today and I strongly recommend buying it. Here is the summary of it:
 Python is a wonderful programming language that is being used more and more in many different industries. It is fast, flexible, and it comes with batteries included.
  Most of the books you read about Python will teach you the language basics – but once you&amp;rsquo;ve learnt them, you’re on your own in designing your application and discovering best practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MariaDB: Writing my first book</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/31/writing-my-first-book-on-mariadb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2014/01/31/writing-my-first-book-on-mariadb/</guid>
      <description>Some of you may already know that I&amp;rsquo;ve been contacted by Packt Publishing to write a book.
As every aware persons asked me why I was contacted, here is the story :
When I was working for Linagora, I gave a training on advanced usage on MySQL/MariaDB. Unfortunately there weren&amp;rsquo;t slides on that subject at this moment and I had to make them all. That&amp;rsquo;s what I did and made an unbranded version for me as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Delivery Ebook</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/02/continuous-delivery-ebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2013/12/02/continuous-delivery-ebook/</guid>
      <description>Puppetlabs recently made a book con Continuous Delivery and offer that book. Continuous delivery allows you to get new features and capabilities to market quickly and reliably. But what is this methodology, really, and what&amp;rsquo;s required to get started? This new, introductory ebook will share:
 What continuous delivery is and isn&amp;rsquo;t Why continuous delivery is important to your business How to get started with the cultural technological changes required to practice continuous delivery  You can download it there</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book : Time Management for System Administrators</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/23/book-time-management-for-system-administrators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/23/book-time-management-for-system-administrators/</guid>
      <description>I red that book a long time ago now and absolutely recommend that book !!!
This is a must have and read ! It helps you to have a good organization in your day to day life as a system administrator. In addition, it will gives you bests practices to accomplish some tasks and rules to stay focus on your work.
I repeat again : if you didn&amp;rsquo;t read that book yet, do it now !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book : Working with MediaWiki</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/19/book-working-with-mediawiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2013/07/19/book-working-with-mediawiki/</guid>
      <description>As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;m a MediaWiki&amp;rsquo;s fan. I manage and use it since 2006 and you can see what I do with on my wiki.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always learned by myself, how to do things on MediaWiki as my needs were classical and for a single user. Some weeks ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a big upgrade for the last company I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for (Linagora) and I wanted to implement interesting features for a multi users usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Livre : Puppet Cookbook</title>
      <link>https://blog.deimos.fr/2012/08/03/livre-puppet-cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.deimos.fr/2012/08/03/livre-puppet-cookbook/</guid>
      <description>J&amp;rsquo;ai commencé à lire ce livre après avoir repensé toute ma conf puppet et c&amp;rsquo;est un peu dommage, j&amp;rsquo;aurais gagné du temps sur certaines choses. Bref ce livre s&amp;rsquo;adresse aux personnes ayant déjà fait du Puppet (normal c&amp;rsquo;est un cookbook), qui veulent automatiser au maximum. Voyez ce bouquin comme un retour d&amp;rsquo;expérience avec les best practices à adopter pour faire une bonne conf Puppet.
Pour vous donner un exemple, ce sera aussi mon retour d&amp;rsquo;expérience, j&amp;rsquo;ai utilisé Puppet pendant 2 ans et demie avec les fonctionnalités classiques et légèrement poussées.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
